[{"question": "Which statement best describes the Sprint Review?(Choose the best answer).", "options": [{"content": "It is a demo at the end of Sprint for everyone in the organization to check on the work done.", "correct": false}, {"content": "It is a mechanism to control the Developers activities during a Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "It is when the Scrum Team and stakeholders inspect the outcome of a Sprint and figure out what to do next.", "correct": true}, {"content": "It is used to congratulate the Developers if they complete their forecast or to punish the Developers if they fail to meet their forecast.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "As the Developers start work during the Sprint, they realize they have selected too much work to finish in the Sprint. What should they do? ( the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "As soon as possible in the Sprint, work with the Product Owner to remove some work or Product Backlog items.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Reduce the Definition of Done and get all of the Product Backlog items done by the new definition.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Find another Scrum Team to give the excess work to.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Inform the Product Owner at the Sprint Review, but prior to the demonstration.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Who must attend the Daily Scrum? ( the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "The Developers and Scrum Master.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Developers and Product Owner.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Developers.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Scrum Team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Master and Product Owner.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "When can Developers cancel a Sprint? (choose the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "They cannot. Only Product Owners can cancel Sprints.", "correct": true}, {"content": "When the Product Owner is absent too often.", "correct": false}, {"content": "When functional expectations are not well understood.", "correct": false}, {"content": "When a technical dependency cannot be resolved.", "correct": false}, {"content": "When the selected Product Backlog items for the Sprint become unachievable.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "\u53ea\u6709PO\u53ef\u4ee5\u53d6\u6d88Sprints"}, {"question": "What happens if the Scrum Team cannot complete its work by the end of the Sprint? ( the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "The Sprint length is unchanged and the Scrum Team continuously learns and adapts", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Sprint is extended temporarily. Lessons are taken to ensure it does not happen again.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Sprint is extended and future Sprints use this new duration.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "What is the Scrum Master responsible for during the Sprint Retrospective? (choose the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "Acting as a scribe to capture the Scrum Team's answers.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Summarizing and reporting the discussions to management.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Prioritizing the resulting action items.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Participating as a Scrum Team member and facilitating as requested or needed.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "A Sprint Retrospective should be held: ( the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "Only when the Scrum Team determines it needs one.", "correct": false}, {"content": "At the end of the last Sprint in a project or a release.", "correct": false}, {"content": "At the end of each Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "At the begining of each Sprint", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "When the Developers determine that they will not be able to finish the complete forecast, who has to be present when reviewing and adjusting the Sprint work selected? (choose the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "The Product Owner and all stakeholders.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Master and the Developers.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Master, project manager and the Developers", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner and the Developers.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "When might a Sprint be cancelled? ( the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "When the sales department has an important new opportunity.", "correct": false}, {"content": "When it becomes clear that not everything will be finished by the end of the Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "When the Developers determine the product plan is infeasible.", "correct": false}, {"content": "When the Sprint Goal becomes obsolete.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "When multiple Scrum Teams are working on a single product, what best describes the Definition of Done? ( the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "The Scrum Masters from each Scrum Team define a common Definition of Done.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Each Scrum Team uses its own, but must make their definition clear to all other teams so the differences are known,", "correct": false}, {"content": "When multiple Scrum Teams are working together on a product, they must mutually define and comply with the same Definition of Done.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Each Scrum Team defines and uses its own. The differences are discussed and reconciled during a hardening Sprint.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "When does a Developer become accountable for the value of a Product Backlog item selected for the Sprint? ( the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "Whenever a team member can accommodate move work", "correct": false}, {"content": "At the Sprint Planning Event.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Never. The entire Scrum Team is accountable for creating value every Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "During the Daily Scrum.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "A Developer takes the Scrum Master aside to express his concerns about data security issues. What should the Scrum Master do? ( the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "Add security to the Definition of Done.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Tell the Product Owner to stop further development of features until the issues are fixed.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Create a Product Backlog item for security.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Go check with the testers.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Ask the Developer to share the concern with the team as soon as possible.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "For which of the following is the Scrum Master responsible? (choose the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "Keeping track of resource allocation.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The meetings and the objectives that a Scrum Team sets for itself.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Managing the performance of the Scrum Team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Properly adopting and using the Scrum framework.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "Who creates the Definition of Done?", "options": [{"content": "The Scrum Master", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Team", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Developers", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Who can cancel a Sprint? ( the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "The Scrum Team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Master", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Stakeholders.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Who determines how many Product Backlog items the Developers select for a Sprint? (choose the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "The Product Owner.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Master.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The stakeholders attending Sprint Planning.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Developers.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Scrum Team", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Who is responsible for the sizing of Product Backlog items? ( the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "The Scrum Master.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The most senior people in the organization, including architects and subject matter experts.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Developers, alone.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Developers after clarifying requirements with the Product Owner.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Product Owner with input from the Developers.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "When multiple Scrum Teams are working on the same product, should all of their Increments be integrated every Sprint? ( the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "Yes, in order to accurately inspect what is done.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Yes, but only for Scrum Teams whose work has dependencies", "correct": false}, {"content": "No. each Scrum Team stands alone.", "correct": false}, {"content": "No, that is far too hard and must be done in a hardening Sprint.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "When does a Developer become accountable for an item in the Sprint Backlog? ( the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "During the Daily Scrum", "correct": false}, {"content": "As soon as a Developer on the Scrum Team can accommodate more work.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Never. All developers on the Scrum Team share accountability for item in the Sprint Backlog.", "correct": true}, {"content": "At Sprint Planning when all of the Sprint Backlog items are split evenly across the Developers.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Who determines how many Product Backlog items the Developers select for a Sprint? ( the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "The Scrum Master.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Developers.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Scrum Team", "correct": false}, {"content": "The stakeholders attending Sprint Planning.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "What is the main reason for the Scrum Master to be at the Daily Scrum? ( the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "They do not have to be there; they only need to ensure the Developers have a Daily Scrum.", "correct": true}, {"content": "To make sure every team member answers the three questions.", "correct": false}, {"content": "To write down any changes to the Sprint Backlog, including adding new items, and tracking progress on the burn-down.", "correct": false}, {"content": "To gather status and progress information to report to management.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "When must a Scrum Team release each Increment? ( the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "When the Scrum Team finishes their work.", "correct": false}, {"content": "When it makes sense to release it.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Whenever the product is free of defects.", "correct": false}, {"content": "After every Sprint, without expection.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "User documentation is part of your Definition of Done. However, there are not enough technical writers for all teams. Your Scrum Team does not have a technical writer. What should the Scrum Team do? ( the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "Form a separate team of technical writers that will work on an on-demand basis for the various Product Owners. Work order will be first in, first out.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Developers on the Scrum Team should write the user documentation.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Let the user documentation remain undone and accumulate until after the last development Sprint. It will then be done by any available technical writers.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Wait until you have a technical writer on your Scrum Team to take care of this.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which statement best describes the Sprint Backlog as the output of the Sprint Planning? ( the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "Every item has a designated owner.", "correct": false}, {"content": "It is ordered by the Product Owner.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Each task is estimated in hours.", "correct": false}, {"content": "It is the Developers plan for the Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "It is a complete list of all work to be done in a Sprint.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "The Developers should have all the skills needed to: ( the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "Turn the Product Backlog items they select into an increment of useful and valuable product functionality.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Complete the product as estimated when the date and cost are committed to the Product Owner.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Do all of the development work, expect for the specialized testing that requires additional tools and enviroments.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "As a team, Developers have all of the skills necessary to create a product Increment."}, {"question": "Who owns the Sprint Backlog? (choose the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "The Scrum Master.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Developers.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "Developers are self-managing, which of the following do they manage? (choose the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "When to release, based on its progress.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Stakeholders for the Sprint Review.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Sprint Backlog.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Sprint length.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Product Backlog ordering", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "When multiple Scrum Teams are working on the same product, should all of their Increments be integrated every Sprint? (choose the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "Yes, but only for Scrum Teams whose work has dependencies.", "correct": false}, {"content": "No, that is far too hard and must be done in a hardening Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "No, each Scrum Team stands alone.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Yes, in order to accurately inspect what is done.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "Which answer best describes the topics covered in Sprint Planning? (choose the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "Who is on the team and what team member roles will be.", "correct": false}, {"content": "What went wrong in the last Sprint and what to do differently this Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "What can be done, how to do it, and why to do it.", "correct": true}, {"content": "What to do and who will do it.", "correct": false}, {"content": "How conditions have changed and how the Product Backlog should evolve.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Five new Scrum Teams have been created to build one product. A few of the Developers on one of the Scrum Teams ask the Scrum Master how to coordinate their work with the other teams. What should the Scrum Master do? ( the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "Collect the Sprint tasks from the teams at the end of their Sprint Planning and merge that into a consolidated plan for the entire Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Visit the five teams each day to inspect that their Sprint Backlogs are aligned.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Teach the Product Owner to work with the lead developers on ordering Product Backlog in a way to avoid too much overlap during a Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Teach them that it is their responsibility to work with the other teams to create an integrated Increment that is inclusive of all five team's work.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "How much of the Sprint Backlog must be defined during the Sprint Planning event? (choose the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "Just enough to understand design and architectural implications.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Just enough tasks for the Scrum Master to be confident in the Developers' understanding of the Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The entire Sprint Backlog must be identified and estimated by the end of Sprint Planning.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Enough so the Developers can create their forecast of what work they can do.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "Who should know the most about the progress toward the Product Goal?\u00a0 (Choose the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "The Developers", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Scrum Master", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Project Manager", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "The Scrum Team should have all the skills needed to: (choose the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "Turn Product Backlog items into a valuable, useful Increment.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Complete the project within the date and cost as calculated by the Product Owner.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Do all of the development work, except for specialized testing that requires additional tools and environments.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "When is the Sprint Backlog created? (choose the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "During Sprint Planning.", "correct": true}, {"content": "During refinement.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Prior to Sprint Planning.", "correct": false}, {"content": "During the Sprint Retrospective", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which of the following services are appropriate for a Scrum Master in regard to the Daily Scrum? (choose the best answer)  ", "options": [{"content": "Lead the discussions.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Make sure that all 3 questions have been answered by each member of the team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Keep track of whether each Developer has a chance to speak.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Teach the Developers to keep the Daily Scrum within 15 minutes.", "correct": true}, {"content": "All of the above.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which of the following are true about the length of the Sprint? ( the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "All Sprints must be one month or less.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The length of the Sprint should be proportional to the work that is done in between Sprints.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Sprint length is determined during Sprint Planning, and should be long enough to make sure the Scrum Team can deliver what is to be accomplished in the upcoming Sprint", "correct": false}, {"content": "Sprint length is determined during Sprint Planning, and should hold the time it will take to build the planned features in the upcoming Sprint, but does not include time for any testing.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which technique is the best way the Scrum Master can ensure that the Developers communicate effectively with the Product Owner? ( the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "Teach the Product Owner about the technologies employed during the Sprints.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Observe communications between them and facilitate direct collaboration.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Teach the Developers to talk in terms of business needs and objectives.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Function as a go-between for them.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Who is accountable for managing the progress of work during a Sprint? (choose the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "The Product Owner.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Developers.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The most junior member of the team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Master.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "When does a Sprint conclude? (Choose the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "When all the tasks are completed by the Developers.", "correct": false}, {"content": "When all Product Backlog items meet their Definition of Done.", "correct": false}, {"content": "When the Product Owner decides enough has been delivered to meet the Sprint Goal.", "correct": false}, {"content": "When the Sprint Retrospective is complete.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "Why is the Daily Scrum held at the same time and same place? ( the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "Rooms are hard to book and must be booked in advance.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The place can be named.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner demands it.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The consistency reduces complexity.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "What is the timebox for the Sprint Review? ( the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "4 hours for a one-month Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "1 day.", "correct": false}, {"content": "As long as needed.", "correct": false}, {"content": "2 hours for a one-month Sprint.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which of these may a Scrum Team deliver at the end of a Sprint? ( the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "A valuable, useful Increment that meets the Definition of Done.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Failing unit tests, to identify acceptance tests for the next Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "An Increment of software with minor known bugs in it.", "correct": false}, {"content": "A single document, if that is what management asked for.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Who should make sure everyone on the Scrum Team does their tasks for the Sprint? (choose the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "The Project Manager.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Master.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Team.", "correct": true}, {"content": "All of the above.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which statement best describes the Sprint Review? (choose the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "It is a mechanism to control the Developers activities during a Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "It is used to congratulate the Developers if they complete their forecast or to punish the Developers if they fall to meet their forecast.", "correct": false}, {"content": "It is when the Scrum Team and stakeholders inspect the outcome of a Sprint and figure out what to do next.", "correct": true}, {"content": "It is a demo at the end of the Sprint for everyone in the organization to check on the work done.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "\u5982\u4e0b\u6458\u81eaScrum Guide\uff1a"}, {"question": "Which approach is best for Scrum Teams in order to produce valuable Increments? (Choose the best answer.)", "options": [{"content": "Each Developer works on the component where they feel that they can contribute. ", "correct": true}, {"content": "Each Scrum Team is accountable for developing functionality from beginning to end. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Each Scrum Team works on an independent set of components. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Each Scrum Member works only as an independent layer of the system. ", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "What is the time-box for the Sprint Review?", "options": [{"content": "As long as needed.", "correct": false}, {"content": "2 hours for a monthly Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "4 hours for a monthly Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "4 hours and longer as needed.", "correct": false}, {"content": "1 day", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "What tactic should a Scrum Team use to divide a group of 100 people into multiple Scrum Teams.(Chose the best answer) ", "options": [{"content": "Create teams based on their skills across multiple layers(Such as database, UI, etc.). ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Ask the Product Owner to assign the people to teams. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Ask the people to divide themselves into teams. ", "correct": true}], "feedback": "\u6709\u65f6\u4f1a\u95eeWhat tactic\uff0c\u6709\u65f6\u4f1a\u95eeWhat is the tactic\uff0c\u9898\u76ee\u4f1a\u53d8\uff0c\u4e0d\u5f71\u54cd\u7b54\u6848\uff0c"}, {"question": "A Product Owner wants advice from the Scrum Master about estimating work in Scrum. Which of these is the guideline that a Scrum Master should give?", "options": [{"content": "Product Backlog items must be estimated in story points.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Estimates are made by the Development Team.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Estimates must be in relative units.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Scrum forbids estimating.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Estimates are made by the Product Owner, but are best checked with the Development Team.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Who is responsible for collaboration with stakeholders? (Choose the best answer) ", "options": [{"content": "The Developers ", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Team ", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Business Analyst. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Project Manager. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Team Manager. ", "correct": false}], "feedback": "\u6700\u597d\u662fPO,\u5982\u679c\u6ca1\u6709\u5c31\u9009\u6574\u4e2aTeam\u3002 "}, {"question": "Five new Scrum Teams have been created to build one product. A few of  the developers on one of the Development Teams ask the Scrum Master how  to coordinate their work with the other teams. What should the Scrum Master do?", "options": [{"content": "Teach the Product Owner to work with the lead developers on ordering  Product Backlog in a way to avoid too much technical and development  overlap during a Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Teach them that it is their responsibility to work with the other teams to create an integrated Increment.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Collect the Sprint tasks from the teams at  the end of their Sprint Planning and merge that into a consolidated plan  for the entire Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Visit the five teams each day to inspect that their Sprint Backlogs are aligned.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "The Sprint Review is mainly an inspect and adapt opportunity for which group?", "options": [{"content": "The Development Team and stakeholders.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner and Development Team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Team and stakeholders.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Product Owner and management.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Development Team and management.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner and stakeholders.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "The Product Owner must release each Increment to production.", "options": [{"content": "When it makes sense.", "correct": true}, {"content": "To make sure the Development Team is done every Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Whenever the product is free of defects.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Without exception.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Upon what type of process control is Scrum based?", "options": [{"content": "Empirical", "correct": true}, {"content": "Complex", "correct": false}, {"content": "Hybrid", "correct": false}, {"content": "Defined", "correct": false}], "feedback": "Scrum is founded on empirical process control theory, or empiricism. Empiricism asserts that knowledge comes from experience and making decisions based on what is observed."}, {"question": "Who is responsible for managing the progress of work during a Sprint?", "options": [{"content": "The Scrum Master.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Development Team.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Product Owner.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The most junior member of the Team.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Marian is the Product Owner envisioning a project for a new release of her product. She made a projection of a release date based upon a sustained velocity of 17 completed units of work per Sprint. Over the first 3 Sprints, the average velocity was 13 for work that the Development Team estimated as 90% done. The Development Teams, feeling the need to meet the plan, figured that a velocity of 17 was within their reach. A good way to continue is:", "options": [{"content": "The Development Team makes sure that all of the selected scope per Sprint is as \u201cDone\u201d as possible. The undone work is estimated and added to the Sprint Backlog of the next Sprint, so it does't mess up the Product Backlog.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Add enough people to the Development Team for the deadline to be made.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The opportunity to inspect and adapt is lost. Opaqueness has replaced transparency. Predictability has dropped below zero. The produced software is not usable. As the rules of Scrum have not been respected, it is the Scrum Master's duty to assess whether repair is possible, or a restart with a more reliable team. If not, the Scrum Master should cancel the project.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Development Team should remind Marian to find funding for enough Release Sprints in which the remaining work can be done", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "When is the Sprint Backlog created?", "options": [{"content": "At the beginning of the project.", "correct": false}, {"content": "During the Sprint Planning meeting.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Prior to the Sprint Planning meeting.", "correct": false}, {"content": "During the Sprint.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "\u65e0"}, {"question": "When a Development Team determines that it will not be able to finish the complete forecast, who has to be present when reviewing and adjusting the Sprint work selected?\u00a0 (Choose the best answer.)", "options": [{"content": "The Development Team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner and all stakeholders.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner and the Development Team.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Scrum Master, project manager and Development Team.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "PO\u5fc5\u987b\u8981\u53c2\u4e0e\u3002"}, {"question": "How should a Development Team deal with non-functional requirements?", "options": [{"content": "Ensure every Increment meets them.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Make sure the release department understands these requirements, but it is not the Development Team\u2019s responsibility.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Handle them during the Integration Sprint preceding the Release Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Assign them to the lead developers on the team.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "How should Product Backlog items be chosen when multiple Scrum Teams work from the same Product Backlog?", "options": [{"content": "The Scrum Team with the highest velocity pulls Product Backlog items first.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Development Teams pull in work in agreement with the Product Owner.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Product Owner should provide each team with its own Product Backlog.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Each Scrum Team takes an equal numbers of items.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner decides.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which best describes the Product Backlog?", "options": [{"content": "It is allowed to grow and change as more is learned about the product and its customers.", "correct": true}, {"content": "It provides just enough information to enable a Scrum team to start the design phase of a product.", "correct": false}, {"content": "It contains all foreseeable tasks and requirements from which the Scrum team can develop and maintain a complete project plan.", "correct": false}, {"content": "It is baselined to follow change management processes.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Who should make sure everyone on the Scrum Team does his or her tasks for the Sprint?", "options": [{"content": "The Project Manager.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Master.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Team. ", "correct": true}, {"content": "All of above ", "correct": false}], "feedback": "\u771f\u9898\uff0c\u5e94\u8be5\u662fDevelopers\uff0c\u5982\u679c\u6ca1\u6709\u5c31\u628a\u6574\u4e2aTeam\u9009\u4e0a\u3002"}, {"question": "How do you know that a Development Team is cross-functional?", "options": [{"content": "Development Team has all the skills to create a potentially releasable increment by the end of every Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "A few of the Development Team members pair program and do Test Driven Development.", "correct": false}, {"content": "There are no conflicts within the Development Team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Every member of the Development Team is able to perform every task.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "What does it mean for Scrum Team to be corss-functional? ", "options": [{"content": "The Scrum Team includes not only developers but also business analysts, architects, and testers. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Developers on the Scrum Team work closely with business analysts, architects, developers, and testers who are not on the team. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Team includes cross-skilled individuals who are able to contribute to do what is necessary to deliver an Increment. ", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Scrum Team is a virtual team drawing from separate teams of business analysts, architects, developers, and testers. ", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which of the following best describes an increment of working software?", "options": [{"content": "A decomposition of all Product Backlog items into tasks for future Sprint Backlog lists.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Additional features in a usable state that complement those delivered in previous iterations.", "correct": true}, {"content": "A new user interface design for functionality delivered in previous iterations.", "correct": false}, {"content": "An automated test suite to verify functionality delivered in previous iterations.", "correct": false}, {"content": "UML diagrams that describe how to deliver functionality in future iterations.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "What is the purpose of a Sprint Review?", "options": [{"content": "To take time to judge the validity of the project.", "correct": false}, {"content": "To inspect the product increment with the stakeholders and collect feedback on next steps.", "correct": true}, {"content": "To review the Scrum Team\u2019s activities and processes during the Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "To build team sprint.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Every Developers should have:", "options": [{"content": "At least one representative from each major software engineering discipline (like QA, Dev, UX).", "correct": false}, {"content": "The competencies and skills needed to deliver a Done Increment in a Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "One Lead Developer and no more than 8 other members.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which statement best describes Scrum?", "options": [{"content": "A defined and predictive process that confirms to the principles of Scientific Management.", "correct": false}, {"content": "A complete methodology that defines how to develop software.", "correct": false}, {"content": "A cookbook that defines best practices for software development.", "correct": false}, {"content": "A framework within which complex products in complex environments are developed.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "How often should Development Team membership change?", "options": [{"content": "As needed, while taking into account a short term reduction in productivity.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Never, because it reduces productivity.", "correct": false}, {"content": "As needed, with no special allowance for changes in productivity.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Every Sprint to promote shared learning.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Who\u00a0determines\u00a0how\u00a0work\u00a0is performed during the Sprint? ", "options": [{"content": "The Scrum Team ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Subject Matter experts. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Team manager. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Developers ", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Scrum Master. ", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "An organization has decided to adopt Scrum, but management wants to  change the terminology to fit with terminology already used. What will  likely happen if this is done? (choose the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "Without a new vocabulary as a reminder of the change, very little change may actually happen.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The organization may not understand what has changed with Scrum and the benefits of Scrum may be lost.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Management may feel less anxious.", "correct": false}, {"content": "All answers apply", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "Who creates a Product Backlog Item\u2019s estimate?", "options": [{"content": "The Development Team after clarifying requirements with the Product Owner.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Product Owner with input from the Development Team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The most senior people in the organization, including architects and subject matter experts.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Master.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Development Team, alone.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "In accordance with Scrum theory, how should a group of 100 people be divided into multiple Development Teams?", "options": [{"content": "Understanding the product, the product vision and the rules of the Scrum framework, the group divides itself into teams.", "correct": true}, {"content": "It doesn\u2019t really matter because you can rotate the teams every Sprint to spread knowledge.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Check with the allocation department to see who has worked together before and make these the first teams.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Create a matrix of skills, seniority, and level of experience to assign people to teams.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "When can a Development Team cancel a Sprint?", "options": [{"content": "It can\u2019t. Only Product Owners can cancel Sprints.", "correct": true}, {"content": "When functional expectations are not well understood.", "correct": false}, {"content": "When the Product Owner is absent too often.", "correct": false}, {"content": "When the selected Product Backlog items for the Sprint become unachievable.", "correct": false}, {"content": "When a technical dependency cannot be resolved.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Who is accountable for tracking the remaining work toward the Sprint Goal?\u00a0 (Choose the best answer.)", "options": [{"content": "The Developers.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Scrum Master.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Project Manager.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "When must a Product Owner release each Increment?\u00a0 (Choose the best answer.)", "options": [{"content": "When it makes sense.", "correct": true}, {"content": "When the Scrum Team finishes their work.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Whenever the product is free of defects.", "correct": false}, {"content": "After every Sprint, Without exception", "correct": false}], "feedback": "\u65e0"}, {"question": "Upon\u00a0what\u00a0type\u00a0of\u00a0process\u00a0control\u00a0is\u00a0Scrum\u00a0based? (choose\u00a0the\u00a0best\u00a0answer)", "options": [{"content": "Defined", "correct": false}, {"content": "Empirical", "correct": true}, {"content": "Hybrid", "correct": false}, {"content": "Complex", "correct": false}], "feedback": "Scrum\u00a0is\u00a0founded\u00a0on\u00a0empirical\u00a0process\u00a0control\u00a0theory,\u00a0or\u00a0empiricism.\u00a0Empiricism\u00a0asserts\u00a0that\u00a0knowledge"}, {"question": "What is the role of management in Scrum? (Choose the best answer.)", "options": [{"content": "To present the Scrum Teams with insights and resources that help them improve.", "correct": true}, {"content": "To monitor the Development Team\u05d2\u20ac\u2122s productivity.", "correct": false}, {"content": "To identify and remove people that aren\u2018t working hard enough.", "correct": false}, {"content": "To continually monitor staffing levels of the Scrum Team.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "A new developer is having continuing conflicts with existing members of the Scrum Team, which is impacting the delivery of the Increment. If necessary, who is responsible for removing the Developer from the Scrum Team? ", "options": [{"content": "The Scrum Team is responsible.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Scrum Master is responsible, they remove impediments. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "The hiring manager is responsible, they hired the Developer. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner is responsible, they control the return on investment (ROI). ", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "When is the most appropriate for a Scrum Team to change the Definition of Done? (Choose the best answer). ", "options": [{"content": "During Product Backlog refinement. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "During the Sprint Retrospective. ", "correct": true}, {"content": "Prior to starting a new project. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "During Sprint Planning. ", "correct": false}], "feedback": "\u5728Scrum Guide\u4e2d\u6709\u5199\u5230\u3002 "}, {"question": "A member of the Developers takes the Scrum Master aside to express his concerns about data security issues. What should the Scrum Master do?", "options": [{"content": "Add security to the definition of \"Done\".", "correct": false}, {"content": "Tell the Product Owner to stop further development of features until the issues are fixed.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Create a Product Backlog item for security.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Go check with the testers.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Ask the person to share the issue with the team as soon as possible.", "correct": true}], "feedback": "\u91cd\u70b9\u662fAs soon as possible\uff0c\u9700\u8981\u5c3d\u5feb\u89e3\u51b3\u3002 "}, {"question": "The Product Backlog is ordered by:", "options": [{"content": "Items are randomly arranged.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Whatever is deemed most appropriate by the Product Owner.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Risk, where safer items are at the top, and riskier items are at the bottom.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Least valuable items at the top to most valuable at the bottom.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Size, where small items are at the top and large items are at the bottom.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "The Product Owner is accountable for effective Product Backlog management. The Product Backlog is an emergent, ordered list of what is needed to improve the product. It is the single source of work undertaken by the Scrum Team."}, {"question": "Which output from Sprint Planning provides the Development Team with a target and overarching direction for the Sprint?", "options": [{"content": "The Sprint Backlog.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Sprint Goal.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The release plan.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Sprint Review minutes.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "What it the main reason for the Scrum Master to be at the Daily Scrum?", "options": [{"content": "To gather status and progress information to report to management.", "correct": false}, {"content": "To write down any changes to the Sprint Backlog, including adding new items, and tracking progress on the burn-down.", "correct": false}, {"content": "He or she does not have to be there; he or she only has to ensure the Development Team has a Daily Scrum.", "correct": true}, {"content": "To make sure every team member answers the three questions.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Who does the work to make sure Product Backlog items conform to the Definition of Done? ", "options": [{"content": "The Developers ", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Quality Assurance Team. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner ", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Team ", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Master. ", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "You have six teams using a traditional method to deliver a product. Your  management has asked you to start using Scrum. In the initial project  there were separate plans and teams for the layers of a software system,  i.e. one for the front-end, one for the middle tier, one for the  back-end, and one for the interfaces and services. This resembles what  is known as component teams. But you have read that it\u2019s a good idea to  have teams organized by feature.   What are the advantages of keeping component teams while starting Scrum?", "options": [{"content": "There\u2019s less initial disruption than  organizing into new teams. As they start, they will discover what works  best, and how to potentially re-organize towards this.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Component teams generally have the skills needed to create a working Increment of software that provides business value.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Because they have worked together for some time, they are likely able to  start producing shippable Increments faster that new feature teams  would.", "correct": false}, {"content": "There are fewer cross-team dependencies than working in feature teams.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "When\u00a0is\u00a0a\u00a0product\u00a0backlog\u00a0item\u00a0considered\u00a0complete?", "options": [{"content": "At the end of the Sprint ", "correct": false}, {"content": "When the item passes all acceptance criteria ", "correct": false}, {"content": "When the item has gained product sponsor approval ", "correct": false}, {"content": "When the item meets the Definition of Done. ", "correct": true}], "feedback": "Product Backlog Item is considered \"Done\" when it meets the Definition of Done"}, {"question": "What activities would a Product Owner typically undertake in the phase  between the end of the current Sprint and the start of the next Sprint?", "options": [{"content": "There are no such activities. The next Sprint starts immediately after the current Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Refine the Product Backlog.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Work with the Quality Assurance departments on the Increment of the current Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Update the project plan with stakeholders.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "What is the accountability of the Product Owner during Sprint 0?\u00a0 (Choose the best answer.)", "options": [{"content": "There is no such thing as Sprint 0.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Gathering, eliciting, and analyzing the requirements that will be inserted into the Product Backlog.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Make the complete project plan to commit date, budget, and scope to the stakeholders.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Determine the composition of the Development Teams so they have the capacity to deliver the completed forecast.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Make sure enough Product Backlog items are refined to fill the first 3 Sprints.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which topics should be discussed in the Sprint Review?", "options": [{"content": "The Scrum process, and how it was used during the Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Coding and engineering practices.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Sprint results.", "correct": true}, {"content": "All of the above.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "The time-box for a Daily Scrum?", "options": [{"content": "Two minutes per person.", "correct": false}, {"content": "15 minutes.", "correct": true}, {"content": "15 minutes for a 4 week sprint. For shorter Sprints it is usually shorter.", "correct": false}, {"content": "4 hours.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The same time of day every day.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Developments asks their Product Owner to re-order the Product Backlog. The team is waiting for an external supplier to deliver a specific software component. Without that component there won\u2019t be enough work in the next Sprint to occupy the full team. The Product Owner asks the Scrum Master for help. What would be good advice to give the Product Owner?", "options": [{"content": "Remind the Product Owner that his primary concern is the flow of value reflected in the ordering of the Product Backlog.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Tell the Product Owner to re-order the Product Backlog so the work involving the external component can be planned in a separate sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Tell the Product Owner that the Product Backlog should be ordered to maximize utilization of Developments.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Every Scrum Team must have a Product Owner and Scrum Master.", "options": [{"content": "True. Outcomes affected by their participation and availability.", "correct": true}, {"content": "False. A Product Owner can be replaced by a business analyst in the Development Team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "False. A Scrum Master is only required when asked for by the Development Team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "True. Each must be 100% dedicated to the Scrum Team.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Who starts the Daily Scrum?", "options": [{"content": "The person coming in last. This encourages people to be on time and helps to stay within the time-box.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Whoever the Development Team decides should start.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The person who has the token.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Master. This ensures that the Development Team has the meeting and stays within the time-box.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The person who last broke the build.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "When is implementation of a Product Backlog item considered complete?", "options": [{"content": "At the end of the Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "When the item has no work remaining in order to be potentially released.", "correct": true}, {"content": "When QA reports that the item passes all acceptance criteria.", "correct": false}, {"content": "When all work in the Sprint Backlog related to the item is finished.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "What happens if the Developers cannot complete its work by the end of the Sprint?", "options": [{"content": "The Sprint is extended and future Sprints use this new duration.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Sprint length holds and the Developers continuously learns what is actually possible to do within a Sprint of this length.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Sprint is extended temporarily. Lessons are taken to ensure it doesn\u2019t happen again.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "\u5207\u8bb0\u6ce8\u610f\uff0cSprint\u4e0d\u662f\u968f\u4fbf\u53ef\u4ee5\u5ef6\u7684\u3002\u770b\u4e00\u4e0b\u8f7dSprint\u4e2d\u80fd\u4ea4\u4ed8\u4ec0\u4e48\u3002 "}, {"question": "Who is responsible for clearly expressing Product Backlog items?", "options": [{"content": "The Scrum Master, or the Scrum Master may have Developments do it.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Master.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The business analyst who represents the Product Owner in the Development Team.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "What does it mean to say that an event has a time-box?", "options": [{"content": "The event must happen at a set time.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The event must happen by a given time.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The event must take at least a minimum amount of time.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The event can take no more than a maximum amount of time.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "As Developments starts work during the Sprint, it realizes it has selected too much work to finish in the Sprint. What should it do?", "options": [{"content": "Inform the Product Owner at the Sprint Review, but prior to the demonstration.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Find another Scrum Team to give the excess work to.", "correct": false}, {"content": "As soon as possible in the Sprint, work with the Product Owner to remove some work or Product Backlog items.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Reduce the definition of \u201cDone\u201d and get all of the Product Backlog items \u201cDone\u201d by the new definition.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "When should a Sprint Goal be created?", "options": [{"content": "It should have been created in the previous Sprint during Product Backlog refinement.", "correct": false}, {"content": "It must be established before Sprint Planning in order to begin planning.", "correct": false}, {"content": "A Sprint Goal is not mandatory in Scrum.", "correct": false}, {"content": "At any time during the Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "During Sprint Planning.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "You are the Scrum Master of a new, to be developed product. Development is going to require 45 people. What is a good first question for you to suggest the group thinks about when forming into teams?", "options": [{"content": "How will we make sure all teams have the right amount of expertise?", "correct": true}, {"content": "What is the right mixture of senior and junior people on each team?", "correct": false}, {"content": "Who are going to be the team leads?", "correct": false}, {"content": "Who are the subject matter experts on each team?", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "How much work is required of the Developers to complete a Product Backlog item selected during the Sprint Planning?\u00a0 (Choose the best answer). ", "options": [{"content": "All Development work and at least some testing. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "As much as is required to meet the Scrum Teams's Definition of Done. ", "correct": true}, {"content": "A proportional amount of time on analysis, design, development, and testing. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "As much as they can fit into the Sprint, with remaining work deferred to the next Sprint. ", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "The Developers should not be interrupted during the Sprint and the  Sprint Goal should remain intact. These are conditions that foster  creativity, quality and productivity. (Which one the following answers is FALSE?)", "options": [{"content": "As a decomposition of the selected Product Backlog items, the Sprint Backlog changes and may grow as the work emerges.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner can help clarify or optimize the Sprint when asked by the Developers.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Sprint Backlog is fully formulated in the Sprint Planning event and does not change during the Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Developers may work with the Product Owner to add or remove work if  they find themselves with more or less capacity than expected.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "The Sprint Backlog makes visible all of the work that the Developers identify as necessary to meet the Sprint Goal. The Developers modify the Sprint Backlog throughout the Sprint, and the Sprint Backlog emerges during the Sprint."}, {"question": "Every Developments should have:", "options": [{"content": "At least one representative from each major software engineering discipline (like QA, Dev, UX).", "correct": false}, {"content": "The competencies and skills needed to deliver a Done Increment in a Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "One Lead Developer and no more than 8 other members.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "What is the tactic a Scrum Master should use to divide a group of 100 people into multiple Development Teams?", "options": [{"content": "Create teams based on their skills across multiple layers (such as database, UI, etc.)", "correct": false}, {"content": "Ask the Product Owner to assign the people to teams.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Ask the developers to divide themselves into teams.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "Who is responsible for tracking the remaining work of the Sprint?", "options": [{"content": "The Development Team.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Scrum Master.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Project Manager.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Development Team is consultation with the Product Owner.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Who can abnormally terminate a Sprint?", "options": [{"content": "The Scrum Master", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Development Team or its members.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Stakeholders", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which technique is the best way the Scrum Master can ensure that the Development Team communicates effectively with the Product Owner?", "options": [{"content": "Monitor communications between them and facilitate direct collaboration.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Teach the Development Team to talk in terms of business needs and objectives.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Teach the Product Owner about the technologies employed during the Sprints.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Act as a go-between for them.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "A new developer is having continuing conflicts with existing Development Team members and creating a hostile environment. If necessary, who is responsible for removing the team member?", "options": [{"content": "The hiring manager is responsible, because he/she hired the developer.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Manager is responsible, because he/she removes Impediments.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Development Team is responsible, and may need help from the Scrum Master.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Product Owner is responsible, because he/she controls the return on investment (ROI).", "correct": false}], "feedback": "no scrum manager in scrum "}, {"question": "Who has the final decision about the order of items in the Product Backlog?\u00a0 (Choose the best answer.)", "options": [{"content": "The Stakeholders.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Scrum Team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Master.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Developers.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "\u65e0"}, {"question": "What is the recommended size for a Scrum Team? \u00a0(Choose the best answer.)", "options": [{"content": "At least 7.", "correct": false}, {"content": "9", "correct": false}, {"content": "10 or fewer.", "correct": true}, {"content": "7 plus or minus 3.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "\u65e0"}, {"question": "A Development Team asks their Product Owner to re-order the Product  Backlog. The team is waiting for an external supplier to deliver a  specific software component. Without that component there won\u2019t be  enough work in the next Sprint to occupy the full team. The Product  Owner asks the Scrum Master for help. What would be good advice to give the Product Owner?", "options": [{"content": "Remind the Product Owner that his primary concern is the flow of value reflected in the ordering of the Product Backlog.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Tell the Product Owner to re-order the Product Backlog so the work  involving the external component can be planned in a separate sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Tell the Product Owner that the Product Backlog should be ordered to maximize utilization of the Development Team.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "If two Scrum Teams are added to the development of a product that previously had only one Scrum Team, what will be the immediate impact on the productivity of the original Scrum Team?", "options": [{"content": "Its productivity is likely to decrease.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Its productivity is likely to stay the same.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Its productivity is likely to increase.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "During the Sprint Retrospective a Scrum Team has identified several high priority process improvements. Which of the following statements is most accurate?\u00a0 (Choose the best answer.)", "options": [{"content": "The Scrum Team may add items to the Sprint Backlog for the next Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Scrum Team should choose at least one high priority process improvement to place in the Product Backlog.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Team should decline to add a process improvement to the Sprint Backlog when things are running smoothly.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Master selects the most important process improvement and places it in the Sprint Backlog", "correct": false}], "feedback": "\u65e0"}, {"question": "For the purpose of transparency, when does Scrum say a valuable and useful increment must be available?", "options": [{"content": "After the acceptance testing phase.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Before the release Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Every 3 Sprints.", "correct": false}, {"content": "At the end of every Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "When the Product Owner asks to create one.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Who should make sure everyone on the Development Team does his or her tasks for the Sprint?", "options": [{"content": "The Project Manager.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Master.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Development Team.", "correct": true}, {"content": "All of the above.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "The CEO asks the Development Team to add a \u201cvery important\u201d item to a Sprint that is in progress. What should the Development Team do?", "options": [{"content": "Add the item to the current Sprint and drop an item of equal size.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Add the item to the current Sprint without any adjustments.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Inform the Product Owner so he/she can work with the CEO", "correct": true}, {"content": "Add the item to the next Sprint.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "The\u00a0CEO\u00a0asks\u00a0the\u00a0Developers\u00a0to\u00a0add\u00a0a\u00a0\"very\u00a0important\"\u00a0item\u00a0to\u00a0a\u00a0Sprint\u00a0that\u00a0is\u00a0in\u00a0progress. What\u00a0should\u00a0the\u00a0Developers\u00a0do? (choose\u00a0the\u00a0best\u00a0answer)", "options": [{"content": "Inform\u00a0the\u00a0other\u00a0members\u00a0of\u00a0the\u00a0Scrum\u00a0Team\u00a0so\u00a0the\u00a0team\u00a0can\u00a0decide\u00a0what\u00a0to\u00a0do.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Add\u00a0the\u00a0item\u00a0to\u00a0the\u00a0current\u00a0Sprint\u00a0and\u00a0drop\u00a0an\u00a0item\u00a0of\u00a0equal\u00a0size.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Add\u00a0the\u00a0item\u00a0to\u00a0the\u00a0next\u00a0Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Add\u00a0the\u00a0item\u00a0to\u00a0the\u00a0current\u00a0Sprint\u00a0without\u00a0any\u00a0adjustments.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "The\u00a0items\u00a0selected\u00a0for\u00a0a\u00a0Sprint\u00a0have\u00a0been\u00a0selected\u00a0as\u00a0most\u00a0valuable\u00a0with\u00a0the\u00a0Product\u00a0Owner.\u00a0The\u00a0items"}, {"question": "The Scrum Master observes the Product Owner struggling with ordering the Product Backlog. What is an appropriate action for the Scrum Master to take?", "options": [{"content": "Suggest the Product Owner extend the Sprint, so he can have more time to order the Product Backlog.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Suggest that the Development Team does the ordering to be sure that it is a feasible ordering of work.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Offer the Product Owner help in understanding that the goal of ordering the Product Backlog is to maximize value.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Present the Product Owner with an ordered Product Backlog to use.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Encourage the Product Owner to work with the Development Team to see which items technically are fastest to implement.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "Developer\u4e0d\u6392\u5e8f "}, {"question": "When do Development Team members take ownership of a Sprint Backlog item?", "options": [{"content": "At the Sprint planning meeting.", "correct": false}, {"content": "During the Daily Scrum.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Never. All Sprint Backlog Items are \u201cowned\u201d  by the entire Development Team, even though each one may be done by an  individual Development Team member.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Whenever a team member can accommodate more work.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "How much work must a Development Team do to a Product Backlog item it selects for a Sprint?", "options": [{"content": "A proportional amount of time on analysis, design, programming, testing, and documentation. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "As much as it can fit into the Sprint. Any remaining work will be transferred to a subsequent Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "All development work and at least some testing.", "correct": false}, {"content": "As much as it has told the Product Owner will be done for every Product Backlog item it selects in conformance with the definition of \"Done\".", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "Who creates the Definition of Done? (choose the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "The Scrum Master", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Team", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Developers", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Who must attend the Daily Scrum?", "options": [{"content": "The Scrum Master and Product Owner", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Development Team.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Development Team and Product Owner.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Development Team and Scrum Master.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "What\u00a0factor\u00a0should\u00a0be\u00a0considered\u00a0when\u00a0establishing the Sprint length? ", "options": [{"content": "The organization's release schedule. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "The organization has mandated similar length sprints. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "The need for the team to learn based on doing work and measuring results. ", "correct": true}, {"content": "The frequency at which team formation can be changed. ", "correct": false}], "feedback": " "}, {"question": "If burndown charts are used to visualize progress, what do they track?", "options": [{"content": "Accumulated cost.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Individual worker productivity.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Work remaining across time.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Accumulated business value delivered to the customer.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "A Scrum Master is introducing Scrum to a new Development Team. The  Development Team gas decided that a Sprint Retrospective is unnecessary.   What action should the Scrum Master take?", "options": [{"content": "Call a meeting between the Development Team and senior management.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Comply with the decision of the self-organizing team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Consult with the Product Owner to see how he/she feels about the situation.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Begin facilitating productive and useful Sprint Retrospectives.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "For which is the Scrum Master responsible?", "options": [{"content": "Managing the performance of the Scrum Team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The meetings and the objectives that a Scrum Team sets for itself.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum framework being adopted and used properly.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Keeping track of resource allocation.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "The length of a Sprint should be:", "options": [{"content": "Short enough to keep the business risk acceptable to the Product Owner.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Short enough to be able to synchronize the development work with other business events.", "correct": false}, {"content": "No more than one calendar month.", "correct": false}, {"content": "All of the above", "correct": true}], "feedback": "\u65e0"}, {"question": "Which statement best describes a Product Owner\u2019s responsibility?", "options": [{"content": "Maximizing the valuie of the work the Scrum Team does.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Managing the project and ensuring that the work meets the commitments to the stakeholders.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Directing the Developers", "correct": false}, {"content": "Keep stakeholders from distracting the Developers.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "\u65e0"}, {"question": "When many Scrum Teams are working on a single product, what best describes the Definition of Done?(Choose the best answer.)", "options": [{"content": "Each Scrum Team defines and uses its own. The differences are discussed and reconciled during a hardening Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Masters from each Scrum Team define a common Definition of Done.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Each Scrum Team uses its own, but must make their definition clear to all other teams so the differences are known.", "correct": false}, {"content": "All Scrum Teams must have a Definition of Done that makes their combined work potentially releasable.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "Who determines when it is appropriate to update the Sprint Backlog during a Sprint?", "options": [{"content": "The Project Manager.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Developers", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Scrum Team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which answer best describes the topics covered in Sprint Planning?", "options": [{"content": "What to do and who will do it.", "correct": false}, {"content": "How conditions have changed and how the Product Backlog should evolve.", "correct": false}, {"content": "What can be done and how to do it.", "correct": true}, {"content": "What went wrong in the last Sprint and what to do differently this Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Who is on the team and what team member roles will be.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Who creates a Product Backlog item's estimate?", "options": [{"content": "The Developers after clarifying requirements with the Product Owner.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Product Owner with input from the Developers.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The most senior people in the organization, including architects and subject matter experts.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Master.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Developers, alone.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "PBI \u662fDevelopers\u548cPO\u4e00\u8d77\u505a\u7684\u3002 "}, {"question": "Which statement best describes the Sprint Backlog as outcome of the Sprint Planning?", "options": [{"content": "It is a complete list of all work to be done in a Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Every item has a designated owner.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Each task is estimated in hours.", "correct": false}, {"content": "It is the Development Team\u2019s plan for the Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "It is ordered by the Product Owner.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "\u65e0"}, {"question": "What is the key concern when multiple Development Teams are working from the same Product Backlog?", "options": [{"content": "Minimizing dependencies between teams.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Clear definition of requirements.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Meeting original scope projections.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Making sure there it's enough work for everyone on every team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Maximizing velocity.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which of the following activitie will a Product Owner engage in during a Sprint? (Choose the best answer )", "options": [{"content": "Run the Daily Scrum.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Update management on what is being worked on.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Answer questions from the Development Team about items in the current Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Prioritize the Development Team\u2019s work on the Sprint Backlog.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "\u6b64\u9898\u5728\u591a\u9009\u4e2d\u4e5f\u6709\uff0c\u5982\u679c\u90092\u4e2a\uff0c\u5c31\u662f\u56de\u7b54Dev\u7684\u95ee\u9898+\u66f4\u65b0\u7ed9\u7ba1\u7406\u5c42\uff0c\u5982\u679c\u9009\u4e00\u4e2a\u5c31\u9009\u56de\u7b54Dev\u7684\u95ee\u9898\u3002\u8fd92\u79cd\u5f62\u5f0f\u90fd\u4f1a\u5728\u771f\u9898\u4e2d\u51fa\u73b0\uff0c\u9700\u8981\u6ce8\u610f\u3002 "}, {"question": "When many Scrum Teams are working on the same product, should all of their increments be integrated every Sprint?", "options": [{"content": "Yes, but only for Scrum Teams whose work has dependencies.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Yes, otherwise the Product Owners (and stakeholders) may not be able to accurately inspect what is done.", "correct": true}, {"content": "No, each Scrum Team stands alone.", "correct": false}, {"content": "No, that is far too hard and must be done in a hardening Sprint.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "User documentation is part of your definition of \u201cDone\u201d. However, there aren\u2019t enough technical writers for all teams. Your Development Team doesn\u2019t have a technical writer.What should you do?", "options": [{"content": "Form a separate team of technical writers that will work on an on-demand basis for the various Product Owners. Work order will be first in, first out.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Let the user documentation remain undone and accumulate until after the last development Sprint. It will then be done by any available technical writers.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Wait until you have a technical writer on your Development Team to take care of this.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Your Development Team is still responsible for creating user documentation. In this case, the Development Team members will write it.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "What is the accountability of the Product Owner during Sprint 0? (Choose the best answer.)", "options": [{"content": "There is no such thing as Sprint 0.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Gathering, eliciting, and analyzing the requirements that will be inserted into the Product Backlog.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Make the complete project plan to commit date, budget, and scope to the stakeholders.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Determine the composition of the Development Teams so they have the capacity to deliver the completed forecast.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Make sure enough Product Backlog items are refined to fill the first 3 Sprints.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which of these may a Development Team deliver at the end of a Sprint?", "options": [{"content": "Failing unit tests, to identify acceptance tests for the next Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "An increment of software with minor known bugs in it.", "correct": false}, {"content": "An increment of working software that is \u201cdone\u201d.", "correct": true}, {"content": "A single document, if that is what the Scrum Master asked for.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "How much time is required after a Sprint to prepare for the next Sprint?", "options": [{"content": "The break between Sprints is time-boxed to 1 week for 30 day Sprints, and usually less for shorter sprints.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Enough time for the requirements for the next Sprint to be determined and documented.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Enough time for the Development team to finish the testing from the last Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "None. A new Sprint starts immediately following the end of the previous Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "All of the above are allowed depending on the situation.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "What happens if the Development Team cannot complete its work by the end of the Sprint?", "options": [{"content": "The Sprint is extended and future Sprints use this new duration.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Sprint length holds and the Development Team continuously learns what is actually possible to do within a Sprint of this length.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Sprint is extended temporarily. Lessons are taken to ensure it doesn\u2019t happen again.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which of the following might the Scrum Team discuss during a Sprint Retrospective?", "options": [{"content": "Methods of communication.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The way the Scrum Team does Sprint Planning.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Skills needed to improve the Development Team's ability to deliver.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Its Definition of \"Done\".", "correct": false}, {"content": "All of the above.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "Sprint Retrospective should be held:", "options": [{"content": "At the end of each Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "At the beginning of each Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Only when the Scrum Team determines it needs one.", "correct": false}, {"content": "At the end of the last Sprint in a project or a release.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Who is accountable for clearly expressing Product Backlog items?\u00a0 (Choose the best answer.)", "options": [{"content": "The business analyst who represents the Product Owner.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Scrum Master, or the Scrum Master may have the Developers do it.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Master.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "Product Owner\u8d1f\u8d23Product Backlog"}, {"question": "How is management external to the Scrum Team involved in the Daily Scrum?", "options": [{"content": "The Scrum Master speaks on their behalf.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Development Team self-manages and is the only management required at the Daily Scrum.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Management gives an update at the start of each Daily Scrum.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner represents their opinions.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "What is the function or purpose of Management in Scrum? (choose the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "To present the Scrum Teams with insights and resources that help them improve. ", "correct": true}, {"content": "To continually monitor staffing levels of the Scrum Team. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "To identify and remove people that are not working hard enough.", "correct": false}, {"content": "To monitor the progress of the Developers on the Scrum Team.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "\u4e3b\u8981\u8fd8\u662f\u7528\u6765\u652f\u6301\u56e2\u961f\u7684\uff0copen assessment\u4e2d\u6709\u7c7b\u4f3c\u7684\u9898\uff0c\u8003\u8bd5\u65f6\u8868\u8fbe\u65b9\u5f0f\u4f1a\u53d8\u3002 "}, {"question": "Scrum Master is introducing Scrum to a Developments. The Developments gas decided that a Sprint Retrospective is unnecessary. What action should the Scrum Master take?", "options": [{"content": "Call a meeting between the Development Team and senior management.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Comply with the decision of the self-organizing team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Consult with the Product Owner to see how he/she feels about the situation.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Begin facilitating productive and useful Sprint Retrospectives.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "During a Sprint, when is new work or further decomposition of work added to the Sprint Backlog?", "options": [{"content": "When the Product Owner identifies new work.", "correct": false}, {"content": "As soon as possible after they are identified.", "correct": true}, {"content": "When the Scrum Master has time to enter them.", "correct": false}, {"content": "During the Daily Scrum after the Development Team approves them.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "\u5728Sprint\u4e2d\u4e00\u65e6\u53d1\u73b0\u65b0\u4efb\u52a1\u5e76\u505a\u51fa\u8bc6\u522b\uff0c\u968f\u5373\u76f4\u63a5\u52a0\u5230Sprint\u4e2d "}, {"question": "When many Development Teams are working on a single product, what best describes the definition of \u201cDone\u201d?\u00a0 (Choose the best answer.)", "options": [{"content": "Each Development Team defines and uses its own. The differences are discussed and reconciled during a hardening Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "It depends.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Each Development Team uses its own but must make their definition clear to all other teams so the differences are known.", "correct": false}, {"content": "All Development Teams must have a definition of \u201cDone\u201d that makes their combined work potentially releasable.", "correct": true}], "feedback": "\u65e0"}, {"question": "What enhances the transparency of an increment?\u00a0 (Choose the best answer.)", "options": [{"content": "Doing all work needed to meet the definition of \"Done\"", "correct": true}, {"content": "Reporting Sprint progress to the stakeholders daily", "correct": false}, {"content": "Keeping track of and estimating all undone work to be completed in a separate Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Updating Sprint tasks properly in the electronic tracking tool.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "What activities would a Product Owner typically undertake in the phase between the end of the current Sprint and the start of the next Sprint?", "options": [{"content": "There are no such activities. The next Sprint starts immediately after the current Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Refine the Product Backlog.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Work with the Quality Assurance departments on the Increment of the current Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Update the project plan with stakeholders.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Why do the Developers need a Sprint Goal\uff1f ", "options": [{"content": "A Sprint Goal only gives purpose to Sprint 0. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "A Sprint Goal ensure that all the Product Backlog items select for the Sprint implemented. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Sprint Goals are not valuable. Everything is known from the Product Backlog. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "The developers are more focused with common yet specific goal. ", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "What is included in the Sprint Backlog?\u00a0 (Choose the best answer.)", "options": [{"content": "User Stories", "correct": false}, {"content": "Tasks.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Use Cases.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Tests.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Any of the above (or others) which are a decomposition of the selected Product Backlog items.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "What is the Product Owner responsible for during the Sprint Retrospective? ", "options": [{"content": "Participating as a Scrum Team member. ", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Product Owner should not take part in Sprint Retrospective. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Summarizing and reporting the discussions to the stakeholders that they represent in the Scrum Team. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Capturing requirements for the Product Backlog. ", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "What is the time-box for the Sprint Planning meeting?", "options": [{"content": "4 Hours for a monthly Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "8 Hours for a monthly Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Monthly.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Whenever it is done.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "A Scrum Master is working with a Development Team that has members in different physical locations. The Development Team meets in a variety of meeting rooms and has much to do logistically (for example, set up conference calls) before the Daily Scrum. What action should the Scrum Master take?", "options": [{"content": "Allow the Development Team to self-manage and determine for itself what to do.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Set up the meeting and tell the Development Team that is how it will be done.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Ask the Development Team members to alternate who is responsible for meeting setup.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Inform management and ask them to solve it.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "A Product Owner wants advice from the Scrum Master about estimating work in Scrum. What guidance should a Scrum Master give?", "options": [{"content": "Scrum forbids estimating.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Estimates are made by the people doing the work. ", "correct": true}, {"content": "Product Backlog items must be estimated in story points.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Estimates are made by the Product Owner, but are best checked with the Developers.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Estimates must be in relative units.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Why does the Product Owner want the Development Team to adhere to its definition of \"Done\"?", "options": [{"content": "To have complete transparency into what has been done at the end of each Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "To be able to reprimand the team when they don\u2018t meet their velocity goal for the Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "To know what the team will deliver over the next three Sprints.", "correct": false}, {"content": "To predict the team's productivity over time.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "When does the second Sprint start? (Choose the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "Once the architectural changes for the second Sprint are approved by the senior architect", "correct": false}, {"content": "Immedately after the first Sprint", "correct": true}, {"content": "After the Product Backlog items for the second Sprint have been selected.", "correct": false}, {"content": "After the customer completes acceptance testing of the first Sprint.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "If burndown charts are used to visualize progress, what does a trend line through a release burndown chart indicate?\u00a0 (Choose the best answer.)", "options": [{"content": "The evolution of the cost spent on the project.", "correct": false}, {"content": "When all work will be completed to the Scrum Team can be released for other work.", "correct": false}, {"content": "When the work remaining will likely be completed if nothing changes on the Product Backlog or the Development Team.", "correct": true}, {"content": "When the project will be over if the Product Owner removes work that is equal in effort to any new work that is added.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "For the purpose of transparency, when does Scrum say a new increment of working software must be available?", "options": [{"content": "After the acceptance testing phase.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Before the release Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Every 3 Sprints.", "correct": false}, {"content": "At the end of every Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "When the Product Owner asks to create one.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "During a Sprint Retrospective, for what is the Product Owner responsible?", "options": [{"content": "Participating as a Scrum Team member.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Summarizing and reporting the discussions to the stakeholders that he/she represents in the Scrum Team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Capturing requirements for the Product Backlog.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner should not take part in Sprint Retrospectives.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which of the following is an example of an Increment?\u00a0 (Choose the best answer.)", "options": [{"content": "A plan for the overall product release.", "correct": false}, {"content": "A mock-up of the product marketing materials.", "correct": false}, {"content": "A design for the product.", "correct": false}, {"content": "A product roll-out plan.", "correct": false}, {"content": "A valuable, useful set of products featured.", "correct": true}, {"content": "All of the above.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "When is it most appropriate for a Development Team to change the definition of \u201cDone\u201d?", "options": [{"content": "During Spring Planning.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Prior to starting a new Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "During the Sprint Retrospective.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Prior to starting a new project.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which of the following services are appropriate for a Scrum Master in regard to the Daily Scrum?", "options": [{"content": "Lead the discussions of the Development Team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Make sure that all 3 questions have been answered by each member of the team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Keep track of whether each team member has a chance to speak.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Teach the Development Team to keep the Daily Scrum within the 15 minute time-box.", "correct": true}, {"content": "All of the above.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "During\u00a0the\u00a0Sprint\u00a0Retrospective\u00a0a\u00a0Scrum\u00a0Team\u00a0has\u00a0identified\u00a0several\u00a0high\u00a0priority\u00a0process\u00a0improvements.Which\u00a0of\u00a0the\u00a0following\u00a0statements\u00a0is\u00a0most\u00a0accurate?\u00a0 (Choose\u00a0the\u00a0best\u00a0answer.)", "options": [{"content": "The\u00a0Scrum\u00a0Team\u00a0may\u00a0add\u00a0items\u00a0to\u00a0the\u00a0Sprint\u00a0Backlog\u00a0for\u00a0the\u00a0next\u00a0Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The\u00a0Scrum\u00a0Team\u00a0should\u00a0choose\u00a0at\u00a0least\u00a0one\u00a0high\u00a0priority\u00a0process\u00a0improvement\u00a0to\u00a0place\u00a0in\u00a0the\u00a0Product\u00a0Backlog.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The\u00a0Scrum\u00a0Team\u00a0should\u00a0decline\u00a0to\u00a0add\u00a0a\u00a0process\u00a0improvement\u00a0to\u00a0the\u00a0Sprint\u00a0Backlog\u00a0when\u00a0things\u00a0are\u00a0running\u00a0smoothly.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The\u00a0Scrum\u00a0Master\u00a0selects\u00a0the\u00a0most\u00a0important\u00a0process\u00a0improvement\u00a0and\u00a0places\u00a0it\u00a0in\u00a0the\u00a0Sprint\u00a0Backlog", "correct": false}], "feedback": "\u5e94\u8be5\u8003\u8651\u76f4\u63a5\u653e\u5230\u4e0b\u4e00\u4e2aSprint\u4e2d\u4f18\u5316\u3002\u4e0d\u80fd\u76f4\u63a5\u4f18\u5316\u3002 "}, {"question": "Which Scrum Value is affected by a lack of trust in the Scrum Team?", "options": [{"content": "Focus", "correct": false}, {"content": "Respect", "correct": false}, {"content": "Openness", "correct": false}, {"content": "Courage", "correct": false}, {"content": "Commitment", "correct": false}, {"content": "All of the above", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "When is a Sprint over?", "options": [{"content": "When the Product Owner says it is done.", "correct": false}, {"content": "When all Product Backlog items meet their definition of \u201cDone\u201d.", "correct": false}, {"content": "When all the tasks are completed.", "correct": false}, {"content": "When the time-box expires.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "You have six teams using a traditional method to deliver a product. Your management has asked you to start using Scrum. In the initial project there were separate plans and teams for the layers of a software system, i.e. one for the front-end, one for the middle tier, one for the back-end, and one for the interfaces and services. This resembles what is known as component teams. But you have read that it's a good idea to have teams organized by feature. What are the advantages of keeping component teams while starting Scrum?", "options": [{"content": "There's less initial disruption than organizing into new teams. As they start, they will discover what works best, and how to potentially re-organize towards this.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Component teams generally have the skills needed to create a working Increment of software that provides business value.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Because they have worked together for some time, they are likely able to start producing shippable Increments faster that new feature teams would.", "correct": false}, {"content": "There are fewer cross-team dependencies than working in feature teams.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "When many Scrum Teams are working on a single product, what best describes the Definition of Done? (Choose the best answer.)", "options": [{"content": " Each Scrum Team defines and uses its own. The differences are discussed and reconciled during a hardening Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": " The Scrum Masters from each Scrum Team define a common Definition of Done.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Each Scrum Team uses its own, but must make their definition clear to all other teams so the differences are known.", "correct": false}, {"content": "All Scrum Teams must have a Definition of Done that makes their combined work potentially releasable.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "When a Development Team is having trouble delivering a working Increment because they don't understand a functional requirement, what should they do?", "options": [{"content": "Add a specialist to the Development Team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Partially complete the functionality, and discuss the remaining work at the Sprint Review.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Collaborate with the Product Owner to determine what is possible and acceptable.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Defer the work to a more appropriate Sprint.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "The IT manager asks a Scrum Team for a status report desdcribing the progress throughout the Sprint. The Scrum Team asks the Scrum Master for advice. The Scrum Master should: ", "options": [{"content": "Ask the Product Owner to send the manager the report. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Talk to the IT manager and explain that progress in Scrum comes from inspecting an Increment at the Sprint Review. ", "correct": true}, {"content": "Create and deliver the report to the manager herself ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Tell the Scrum Team to figure it out themselves. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Tell the Developers to fit the report into the Sprint Backlog. ", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "The Product Owner determines how many Product Backlog items the Development Team selects for a Sprint.", "options": [{"content": "False.", "correct": true}, {"content": "True, accordingly to what was committed to the stakeholders.", "correct": false}, {"content": "True, but only after confirmation by the resource manager that the Team has enough capacity.", "correct": false}, {"content": "True.", "correct": false}, {"content": "False, the Scrum Master does that.", "correct": false}, {"content": "False, capacity and commitment are the Project manager\u05d2\u20ac\u2122s responsibility.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "How should Product Backlog items be chosed when multiple Scrum Teams work from the same Product Backlog?", "options": [{"content": "The Developers pull in work in agreement with the Product Owner. ", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Product Owner should provide each team with its own Product Backlog. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Team with the highest velocity pulls Product Backlog items first. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner decides. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Each Scrum Team takes an equal number of items. ", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which phrase best describes a Product Owner?", "options": [{"content": "Go-between development team and customers. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Value optimizer. ", "correct": true}, {"content": "Requirements engineer. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Team manager. ", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Who\u00a0should\u00a0know\u00a0the\u00a0most\u00a0about\u00a0the\u00a0progress\u00a0toward\u00a0a\u00a0business\u00a0objective\u00a0or\u00a0a\u00a0release,\u00a0and\u00a0be able\u00a0to\u00a0explain\u00a0the\u00a0alternatives\u00a0most\u00a0clearly? (choose\u00a0the\u00a0best\u00a0answer)", "options": [{"content": "The\u00a0Product\u00a0Owner", "correct": true}, {"content": "The\u00a0Project\u00a0Manager", "correct": false}, {"content": "The\u00a0Developers", "correct": false}, {"content": "The\u00a0Scrum\u00a0Master", "correct": false}], "feedback": "The\u00a0Product\u00a0Owner\u00a0is\u00a0the\u00a0sole\u00a0person\u00a0responsible\u00a0for\u00a0ordering\u00a0the\u00a0Product\u00a0Backlog.\u00a0Their"}, {"question": "What is the function or purpose of Management in Scrum?", "options": [{"content": "Monitor the progress of the Developers on the Scrum Team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Identify and remove people that are not working hard enough.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Support the Product Owner with insights and information into high value  product and system capabilities. Support the Scrum Master to encourage  organizational change that fosters empiricism, self-management,  bottom-up intelligence, and intelligent product delivery.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Continually monitor staffing levels of the Scrum Team.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "Management has no official role or accountability on a Scrum Team. However, management external to the Scrum Team is relevant in setting the vision and strategy to guide the overall direction of the organization."}, {"question": "When must the Product Owner participate in the Daily Scrum? ", "options": [{"content": "When the Scrum Master asks the Product Owner to attend. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "When the Product Owner is actively working on items on the Sprint Backlog; however, they participate as a Developer. ", "correct": true}, {"content": "When there are impediments to discuss. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "When the Product Owner needs to represent the stakeholders' point of view to the Developers. ", "correct": false}], "feedback": "Scrum Guide\u4e2d\u6709\u539f\u6587\u3002if th Product owner or Scrum Master are actively working on items in the Sprint Backlog, they participates as Developers. "}, {"question": "When\u00a0does\u00a0the\u00a0next\u00a0Sprint\u00a0begin? (choose\u00a0the\u00a0best\u00a0answer)", "options": [{"content": "When\u00a0the\u00a0Product\u00a0Owner\u00a0is\u00a0ready.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Immediately\u00a0after\u00a0the\u00a0conclusion\u00a0of\u00a0the\u00a0previous\u00a0Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Next\u00a0Monday.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Immediately\u00a0following\u00a0the\u00a0next\u00a0Sprint\u00a0Planning.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "A\u00a0new\u00a0Sprint\u00a0starts\u00a0immediately\u00a0after\u00a0the\u00a0conclusion\u00a0of\u00a0the\u00a0previous\u00a0Sprint."}, {"question": "Developers\u00a0are\u00a0self-managing, which of following do they manage? ", "options": [{"content": "Sprint length ", "correct": false}, {"content": "When to release, based on its progress ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Stakeholders for the Sprint Review ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Product Backlog ordering ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Sprint Backlog. ", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "Which outcome is expected as Scrum Teams mature?", "options": [{"content": "They will improve their definition of \u201cDone\u201d to include more stringent criteria.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Sprint Retrospectives will grow to be longer than 4 hours.", "correct": false}, {"content": "There is no need for a time-boxed Sprint, since time-boxes are only for new Scrum Teams.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Sprint Reviews will no longer be needed.", "correct": false}, {"content": "A Scrum Master is no longer needed since they are a mature team now.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "As the Development Team starts work during the Sprint, it realizes it has selected too much work to finish in the Sprint. What should it do?", "options": [{"content": "Inform the Product Owner at the Sprint Review, but prior to the demonstration.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Find another Scrum Team to give the excess work to.", "correct": false}, {"content": "As soon as possible in the Sprint, work with the Product Owner to remove some work or Product Backlog items.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Reduce the definition of \"Done\" and get all of the Product Backlog items \"Done\" by the new definition.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "User documentation is part of your definition of \"Done\". However, there aren\u2019t enough technical writers for all teams. Your Development Team doesn\u2019t have a technical writer. What should you do?", "options": [{"content": "Form a separate team of technical writers that will work on an on-demand basis for the various Product Owners. Work order will be first in, first out.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Let the user documentation remain undone and accumulate until after the last development Sprint. It will then be done by any available technical writers.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Wait until you have a technical writer on your Development Team to take care of this.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Your Development Team is still responsible for creating user documentation. In this case, the Development Team members will write it.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "The three pillars of empiricism are: (choose the best answer)", "options": [{"content": "Planning, Inspection, Adaptation.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Transparency, Eliminating Waste, Kaizen.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Inspection, Transparency, Adaptation.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Planning, Demonstration, Retrospective.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Respect For People, Kaizen, Eliminating Waste.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "Scrum is founded on empirical process control theory, or empiricism. Empiricism asserts that knowledge comes from experience and making decisions based on what is known."}, {"question": "Sprint burndown charts are an efficient tracking tool, because they show:", "options": [{"content": "An estimate of the total work remaining for the Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "How much effort has gone into a Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "How many hours have been worked by each Development Team member.", "correct": false}, {"content": "How many Product Backlog items remain.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "\u5173\u952e\u8bcd\u662fSprint burndown chart\uff0c\u591a\u4e86\u4e00\u4e2aSprint\uff0c\u4e0d\u662f\u666e\u901a\u7684burndown chart\u3002 "}, {"question": "\u3010\u6b64\u9898\u8bf7\u5ffd\u7565\uff0c\u8001\u63d0\uff0c\u4e0d\u4f1a\u518d\u8003\u4e86\u3011Who creates the definition of \u201cDone\u201d?", "options": [{"content": "The Scrum Master as he/she is responsible for the Development Team\u2019s productivity.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Team, in a collaborative effort where the result is the common denominator of all members\u2019 definition.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner as he/she is responsible for the product\u2019s success.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The development organization (or Development Team if none is available from the development organization).", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "During Sprint Planning the Product Owner and the Developers are unable to reach an understanding about the highest order Product Backlog items. Because of this, the Developers are unable to determine how many Product Backlog items they can forecast for the upcoming Sprint. However, the Product Owner and the Developers are able to agree on a Sprint Goal. Which of the following actions should the Scrum Master support? (choose the best two answers)  ", "options": [{"content": "Cancel the Sprint. Send the entire team to an advanced Scrum training and then start a new Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "During the next Sprint Retrospective discuss why this happened and what changes will make it less likely to recur.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Continue the Sprint Planning event past its timebox until an adequate number of Product Backlog items are well enough understood for the Developers to make a complete forecast. Then start the Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Forecast the Product Backlog items that are most likely to meet the Sprint Goal and create the Sprint Backlog. Conclude Sprint Planning and start the development work. Continue to analyze, decompose, and create additional functionality during the Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Ask everyone to take as much time as needed to analyze the Product Backlog first, and then reconvene another Sprint Planning meeting.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "A Scrum Team is required to deliver a done Increment by the end of a Sprint. Select two statements that explain what done means. ( the best two answers)", "options": [{"content": "Ready to be released to end users.", "correct": true}, {"content": "No work is left to meet the Definition of Done.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Ready for integration.", "correct": false}, {"content": "All work the Developers are willing to do.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Whatever the Product Owner defines as quality.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which of the following are topics for the Developers to discuss at the Daily Scrum as they Inspect their progress toward the Sprint Goal?\u00a0 (Choose the best three answers)", "options": [{"content": "Are there any decisions they need to be made to maintain progress toward the Sprint Goal?", "correct": true}, {"content": "How many hours did I spend on the project yesterday?", "correct": false}, {"content": "What have we learned since yesterday, and how should we modify our plan to Increase our ability to meet the Sprint Goal?", "correct": true}, {"content": "Why were you late?", "correct": false}, {"content": "Will today's work negatively Impact our ability to meet the Sprint Goal for the Sprint following this one?", "correct": false}, {"content": "What will I be working on tomorrow?", "correct": false}, {"content": "Are there any impediment blocking progress toward the Sprint Goal?", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "During Sprint Planning the Product Owner and the Developers are unable to reach a clear understanding about the highest order Product Backlog items. Because of this, the Developers are unable to detemine how many Product Backlog items they can forecast for the upcoming Sprint. However, the Product Owner and the Developers are able to agree on a Sprint Goal.\u00a0 Which of the following actions should the Scrum Master support? (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "Forecast the most likely Product Backlog items to meet the goal and create a Sprint Backlog based on a likely initial design and plan. Once the time-box for the Sprint Planning meeting is over, start the Sprint and continue to analyze, decompose, and create additional functionality during the Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Cancel the Sprint. Send the entire team to an advanced Scrum training and then start a new Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Continue the Sprint Planning meeting past its time-box until an adequate number of Product Backlog items are well enough understood for the Development Team to make a complete forecast. Then start the Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Ask everyone to take as much time as needed to analyze the Product Backlog first, and then reconvene another Sprint Planning meeting.", "correct": false}, {"content": "During the next Sprint Retrospective discuss why this happened and what changes will make it less likely to recur.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "As the Sprint Planning progresses, the Developers realize that the workload may be greater than their capacity to complete the work. Which two are valid actions? (choose the best two answers)", "options": [{"content": "Remove or change selected Product Backlog items.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Developers work overtime during this Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Cancel the Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Developers ensure that the Scrum Team is aware, start the Sprint, and monitor progress.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Recruit additional Developers before the work can begin.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "What are two effective ways for the Scrum Team to make non-functional requirements visible? ( the best two answers)", "options": [{"content": "Run the integration and regression tests before the end of the Sprint, and capture the open work for the Sprint Backlog of the next Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Add them to the Product Backlog to ensure transparency.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Put them on a separate list on the Scrum board, available for all to see.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Add them to the Definition of Done so the work is taken care of every Sprint.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "A Scrum Team is a cohesive unit of professionals that consists of which of the following? (Choose all that apply)", "options": [{"content": "One Scrum Master", "correct": true}, {"content": "Customers", "correct": false}, {"content": "Developers", "correct": true}, {"content": "One Product Owner", "correct": true}, {"content": "Users.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "SM\uff0cPO\uff0cDevelopers"}, {"question": "What are three ways Scrum promotes self-management? ( the best three answers)", "options": [{"content": "By being a lightweight framework.", "correct": true}, {"content": "By the Scrum Team deciding what work to do in a Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "By removing titles for Scrum Team members.", "correct": true}, {"content": "By having the Scrum Master protect the Scrum Team from interruptions.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "At the end of a Sprint, a Product Backlog item worked on during the Sprint does not meet the Definition of Done. What two things should happen with the undone Product Backlog item? (Choose the best two answers).", "options": [{"content": "Review the item, add the done part of the estimate to the velocity and create a Story for the remaining work.", "correct": false}, {"content": "If the stakeholders agree, the Product Owner can accept it and release it to the users.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Do not include the item in the Increment this Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Put it on the Product Backlog for the Product Owner to decide what to do with it.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "You are the Scrum Master for four Scrum Teams working from the same Product Backlog. Several of the developers come to you complaining that work identified for the upcoming two Sprints will require full-time commitment from a specialist who is external to the teams. What should the Scrum Master consider in this situation? (choose the best two answers)", "options": [{"content": "The ability of the Scrum Teams to produce integrated Increments.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The desire to maintain a stable velocity.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The need to have enough work to keep all Developers busy.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The benefit of Developers figuring out a solution for themselves.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "Which two things should the Scrum Team do during the first Sprint? (choose the best two answers)", "options": [{"content": "Analyze, describe, and document the requirements for the subsequent Sprints.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Make up a plan for the rest of the project.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Build at least one piece of valuable functionality.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Create at least one valuable, useful Increment.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Define the major product features and a release plan architecture.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "During the Sprint, the Scrum Master's roles is to do which two of the following:(Choose the best two answer)", "options": [{"content": "Ensure the product Owner attends all Scrum events.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Facillitate inspection and adaption opptuntities as requested or needed.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Assign tasks with the Scrum Team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Monitor the progressof the Developers.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Coaching the team members in self-management.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Escalate team conflicts to functional line managers.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which Scrum Values are violated by building Product Backlog items that have low business value? (choose the best three answers)", "options": [{"content": "Courage.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Focus.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Respect.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Economic Value Added.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Earned Value.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "At the seventh Sprint Review, the stakeholders are disappointed and angry. They have determined that the product or system being built will not meet their needs and will cost more than they are willing to spend. What factors likely led to this? ( the best two answers)", "options": [{"content": "The Product Owner has not been keeping the stakeholders aware of the progress of the project.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The stakeholders were not allowed to prioritize Product Backlog items.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The stakeholders have not been using the Sprint Reviews to inspect and evaluate progress.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Project Management Office (PMO) has not been engaged adequately.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "1\uff09\u6ca1\u6709\u8ba9Stakeholder\u4e86\u89e3\u9879\u76ee\u8fdb\u7a0b"}, {"question": "The Dally Scrum is an event that happens every day. What would be three key concerns If the frequency were to be lowered to every two or three days? ( the best three answers)", "options": [{"content": "Opportunities to inspect and adapt the Sprint Backlog are lost.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Scrum Master loses the ability to update the Gantt chart properly.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Too much work is spent updating the Scrum board before the meeting.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Sprint Backlog may become inaccurate.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Impediments are raised and resolved more slowly.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Product Owner cannot accurately report progress to the stakeholders", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "What are three benefits of self-management? (choose the best three answers)", "options": [{"content": "Increased rule compliance.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Increased accuracy of estimates.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Increased self-accountability.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Increased creativity.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Increased commitment.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "Which three of the following are true about Scrum? (Choose the best three answers)", "options": [{"content": "Scrum is based on empirclsm and lean thinking.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Each component of Scrum serves a specific purpose and is essential to Scrum's success and your usage of Scrum to develop complex product.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Scrum implements self-management by replacing Project Managers with Scrum Masters.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Scrum is a framework for developing and sustaining complex products.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Scrum is a methodology where you can pick and choose which parts of Scrum you think will work for your environment.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "You are the Scrum Master on a newly formed Scrum Team. Which two of the following activites would probably help the team in starting up?\u00a0 (Choose the best two answers).", "options": [{"content": "Ensure the Scrum Team members have compatible personalities.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Introduce a bonus system for the top performers in the team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Ensure the team understands they need a Definition of Done.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Have the manager for each Developer introduce their direct reports and go over their responsibilities on the Scrum Team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Ask the Product Owner to discuss the product, its vision, history, goals, and context, as well answer questions.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "What\u00a0techniques\u00a0could\u00a0the\u00a0Scrum\u00a0Master\u00a0use\u00a0when\u00a0the\u00a0Scrum\u00a0Team\u00a0gets\u00a0caught\u00a0in\u00a0an\u00a0internal\u00a0disagreement\u00a0about\u00a0which\u00a0agile\u00a0practices\u00a0to\u00a0apply?\u00a0(Choose\u00a0the\u00a0best\u00a0two\u00a0answers.)", "options": [{"content": "Involve\u00a0the\u00a0complete\u00a0Scrum\u00a0Team\u00a0in\u00a0making\u00a0a\u00a0decision.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Use\u00a0coaching\u00a0techniques;\u00a0such\u00a0as\u00a0open\u00a0QUESTION\u00a0NO:s\u00a0and\u00a0active\u00a0listening.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Ask\u00a0an\u00a0external\u00a0agile\u00a0coach\u00a0what\u00a0they\u00a0recommend.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Ask\u00a0team\u00a0members\u00a0to\u00a0take\u00a0the\u00a0issue\u00a0up\u00a0with\u00a0to\u00a0the\u00a0company\u2019s\u00a0Human\u00a0Resources\u00a0department.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "A Scrum Team is experiencing a growing list of impediments. Which techniques would be most helpful in this situation?  (Select two..)", "options": [{"content": "The Product Owner should add the open impediments to the Product Backlog. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "As a Scrum Team, prioritize the list and work on them in order. ", "correct": true}, {"content": "Arrange a triage meeting with management. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Master discusses the impediments with the Scrum Team. ", "correct": true}], "feedback": "\u8fd9\u662f\u4e00\u6a21\u4e00\u6837\u7684\u8003\u9898\u3002C\u80af\u5b9a\u4e0d\u5bf9\uff0cA\u7b54\u6848\u5f88\u5177\u8ff7\u60d1\u6027\uff0c\u4f46\u8fd9\u91cc\u8981\u9009\u51fa\u6700\u5408\u9002\u7684\u4e24\u4e2a\uff0c\u6545\u4e3aB\u548cD\u3002 "}, {"question": "Which are appropriate topics for discussion in a Sprint Retrospective?\u00a0 (Choose the best three answers.)", "options": [{"content": "Arranging the Sprint Backlog for the next Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The value of work currently represented in the Product Backlog.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Team relations", "correct": true}, {"content": "Definition of Done.", "correct": true}, {"content": "How the Scrum Team does its work.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "Which three questions might be answered by Development Team members at the Daily Scrum?\u00a0 (Choose three.)", "options": [{"content": "How is the Sprint proceeding?", "correct": false}, {"content": "What did I do yesterday that helped the Development Team meet the Sprint Goal?", "correct": true}, {"content": "Why were you late?", "correct": false}, {"content": "What will I do today to help the Development Team meet the Sprint Goal?", "correct": true}, {"content": "How many hours did I spend on the project yesterday?", "correct": false}, {"content": "What will I be working on tomorrow?", "correct": false}, {"content": "Do I see any impediment that prevents me or the Development Team from meeting the Sprint Goal?", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "The Definition of Done serves which three purposes? (choose the best three answers).", "options": [{"content": "Describe the work that must be done before the Sprint is allowed to end.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Describe the purpose, objective, and time-box of each Scrum event.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Increase transparency.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Create a shared understanding of when work is complete.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Guide the Developers on how many Product Backlog items to select for the Sprint.", "correct": true}], "feedback": "\u9898\u76ee\u4f1a\u6362\u4e00\u4e2a\u95ee\u7684\u65b9\u5f0f\uff0c\u4e0d\u5f71\u54cd\u7b54\u6848\uff0c\u9700\u8981\u7406\u89e3\u7b54\u6848\u3002 "}, {"question": "You are the Scrum Master on a newly formed Scrum Team.   Which three of the following activities would probably help the team in starting up? (Choose three.)", "options": [{"content": "Introduce a bonus system for the top performers in the team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Have the Scrum Team members introduce themselves to each other and give a brief background of their skills and work history.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Have the development managers for each Development Team member introduce their direct reports and go over their responsibilities on the Scrum Team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Ensure the Scrum Team members have compatible personalities.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Ensure the team understands they need a definition of \u201cDone\u201d.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Ask the Product Owner to discuss the product or project, its history, goals, and context, as well as answer questions.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "Which two ways of creating Development Teams are consistent with Scrum\u2019s values?\u00a0 (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "Existing teams propose how they would like to go about organizing into the new structure.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Managers personally re-assign current subordinates to new teams.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Managers collaborate to assign individuals to specific teams.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Bring all the developers together and let them self-organize into Development Teams.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Chief Product Owner determines the new team structures and assignments.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "What are three ways Scrum promotes self-organization?\u00a0 (Choose three.)", "options": [{"content": "By not allowing documentation.", "correct": false}, {"content": "By the Development Team deciding what work to do in a Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "By preventing stakeholders from entering the development room.", "correct": false}, {"content": "By removing titles for Development Team members.", "correct": true}, {"content": "By being a lightweight framework.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "As the Sprint Planning meeting progresses, the Development Team sees that the workload is greater than they can handle. Which two are valid actions?\u00a0 (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "Recruit additional Development Team members before the work can begin.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Development Team ensures that the Product Owner is aware, starts the Sprint, and monitors progress. ", "correct": true}, {"content": "Cancel the Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Remove or change selected Product Backlog items.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Development Team works overtime during this Sprint.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "What are two responsibilities of testers in a Development Team?\u00a0 (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "Verifying the work of programmers.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Everyone in the Development Team is responsible for quality.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Tracking quality metrics.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Finding bugs.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Scrum has no \u201ctester\u201d role.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "Which three purposes does the definition of \"Done\" serve?\u00a0 (Choose the best three answers.)", "options": [{"content": "Guide the Development Team on how many Product Backlog items to select for the Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Create a shared understanding of when work is complete.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Describe the purpose, objective, and time-box of each Scrum event.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Describe the work that must be done before the Sprint is allowed to end.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Increase transparency.", "correct": true}], "feedback": "\u8003\u8bd5\u4e2d\u51fa\u73b0\u7684\u6982\u7387\u6781\u5927\uff0c\u7b54\u6848\u662fABE\u3002C\u4e0d\u662f\u5fc5\u987b\u7684\uff0cD\u662f\u9519\u8bef\u7684\uff0c\u5982\u679c\u9898\u76ee\u91cc\u9762\u6709must\u8fd9\u79cd\u592a\u7edd\u5bf9\u7684\u8bcd\uff0c\u5fc5\u987b\u8981\u6ce8\u610f\uff0c\u6781\u5927\u6982\u7387\u662f\u9519\u8bef\u9009\u9879\u3002 "}, {"question": "A Scrum Team has been working on a product for nine Sprints. A new Product Owner comes in, understanding he is accountable for the Product Backlog. However, he is unsure about his responsibilities. Which two activities are part of the Product Owner role according to Scrum?\u00a0 (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "Ensuring that the most valuable functionality is produced first, at all times.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Interacting with stakeholders.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Providing the Development Team with detailed specifications.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Describing features as Use Cases.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Creating detailed functional test cases.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "You are the Scrum Master on a newly formed Scrum Team. Which three of the following activities would probably help the team in starting up?\u00a0 (Choose three.)", "options": [{"content": "Introduce a bonus system for the top performers in the team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Have the Scrum Team members introduce themselves to each other and give a brief background of their skills and work history.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Have the development managers for each Development Team member introduce  their direct reports and go over their responsibilities on the Scrum  Team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Ensure the Scrum Team members have compatible personalities.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Ensure the team understands they need a definition of \u201cDone\u201d.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Ask the Product Owner to discuss the product or project, its history, goals, and context, as well as answer questions.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "In the Sprint Planning meeting, the Product Owner and the Development  Team were unable to reach a clear understanding about the highest order  Product Backlog items. Because of this, the Development Team couldn\u2019t  figure out how many Product Backlog items it could forecast for the  upcoming Sprint. They were able to agree on a Sprint Goal, however. Which of the following two actions should the Scrum Master support? (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "Cancel the Sprint. Send the entire team to an advanced Scrum training and then start a new Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Forecast the most likely Product Backlog  items to meet the goal and create a Sprint Backlog based on a likely  initial design and plan. Once the time-box for the Sprint Planning  meeting is over, start the Sprint and continue to analyze, decompose,  and create additional functionality during the Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Continue the Sprint Planning meeting past its time-box until an adequate  number of Product Backlog items are well enough understood for the  Development Team to make a complete forecast. Then start the Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Discuss in the upcoming Sprint Retrospective why this happened and what changes will make it less likely to recur.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Ask everyone to take as much time as needed to analyze the Product  Backlog first, and then reconvene another Sprint Planning meeting.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "What techniques could the Scrum Master use when the Scrum Team gets  caught in an internal disagreement about which agile practices to apply?\u00a0 \u00a0(Choose the best two answers.)", "options": [{"content": "Involve the complete Scrum Team in making a decision.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Use coaching techniques; such as open QUESTION NO:s and active listening.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Ask an external agile coach what they recommend.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Ask team members to take the issue up with to the company\u2019s Human Resources department.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Select two ways in which technical debt impacts transparency.\u00a0 (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "When calculated and estimated, the total amount of technical debt shows  exactly how long until the Product Owner can release the Increment.", "correct": false}, {"content": "It leads to false assumptions about the  current state of the system, specifically of an Increment being  releasable at the end of a Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "As development progresses and code is  added, the system becomes more difficult to stabilize, which results in  future work being slowed down in unpredictable ways.", "correct": true}, {"content": "It enhances transparency for the Product Owner as a Development Team is  not allowed to do additional feature development in a Sprint as long as  there is technical debt.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which of the following are true about the Product Owner role?\u00a0 (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "The Product Owner is one person.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Product Owner is accountable for ordering the Product Backlog.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Multiple people can share the Product Owner role on a Scrum Team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner role can be played by a committee or a team of people.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "\u65e0"}, {"question": "During a Sprint Retrospective, The Developers proposes moving the Daily Scrum to only occur on Tuesdays and Thursdays. Which two are the most appropriate responses for the Scrum Master?\u00a0 (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "Consider the request and decide on which days the Daily Scrum should occur.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Coach the team on why the Daily Scrum is important as an opportunity to update the plan.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Have the developers vote.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Learn why the Development Team wants this and work with them to improve the outcome of the Daily Scrum.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Acknowledge and support the self-organizing team\u2019s decision.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "\u65e0"}, {"question": "What are three benefits of self-organization?\u00a0 (Choose the best three answers.)", "options": [{"content": "Increased creativity.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Increased rule compliance.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Increased accuracy of estimates.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Increased self-accountability", "correct": true}, {"content": "Increased commitment.", "correct": true}], "feedback": "\u6b7b\u8bb0\u786c\u80cc\u5427\u3002 "}, {"question": "Choose two responsibilities of a self-organizing Development Team.\u00a0 (Choose the best two answers.)", "options": [{"content": "Reorder the Product Backlog.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Pull Product Backlog items for the Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Do the work planned in the Sprint Backlog.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Increase velocity.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Report daily progress to stakeholders.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which\u00a0of\u00a0the\u00a0following\u00a0are\u00a0the\u00a0developers\u00a0accountable\u00a0for?", "options": [{"content": "Reporting productivity ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Selecting the Product Owner ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Creating a plan for the Sprint, the Sprint Backlog ", "correct": true}, {"content": "Organizing the work required to meet the Sprint Goal ", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "Which of the following is required by Scrum? (Choose all that apply.)", "options": [{"content": "Sprint Retrospective.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Members must be stand up at the Daily Scrum.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Sprint Burndown Chart.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Release planning.", "correct": false}, {"content": "All of the above.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which two things are appropriate for a Scrum Master to do if the Scrum Team doesn't have the tools and environment to completely finish each selected Product Backlog item?\u00a0 (Choose the best two answers.)", "options": [{"content": "Coach the ScrumTeam to improve its skills, tools, and infrastructure over time and adjust the Definition of \"Done\" accordingly.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Encourage the Product Owner to accept partially \"Done\" increments until the situation improves.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Refocus the current Sprint on establishing the Scrum Team's environment instead of delivering an Increment.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Declare the Scrum Team not ready for Scrum.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Have the Scrum Team establish a Definition of \"Done\" that is actually possible to achieve given current circumstances.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "At the seventh Sprint Review, the stakeholders are disappointed and angry. They have determined that the product or system being built will not meet their needs and will cost more than they are willing to spend. What factors likely led to this? (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "The Project Management Office (PMO) has not been engaged adequately.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner has not been keeping the stakeholders aware of the progress of the project.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The stakeholders haven\u2019t been using the Sprint Reviews to inspect and evaluate progress.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The stakeholders were not allowed to enter the development area.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Commitment\u00a0is\u00a0essential to achieve the benefits of Scrum. What actions demostrate the commitment of Scrum Team members\uff1f ", "options": [{"content": "Always deliver the item in the Sprint forecast. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Do your best work ", "correct": true}, {"content": "Help your fellow Scrum Team members. ", "correct": true}, {"content": "Work late. ", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which of the following are roles on a Scrum Team?\u00a0 (Choose all that apply.)", "options": [{"content": "Users", "correct": false}, {"content": "Scrum Master", "correct": true}, {"content": "Product Owner", "correct": true}, {"content": "Developers", "correct": true}, {"content": "Customers", "correct": false}], "feedback": "\u65e0"}, {"question": "Which three questions might be answered by Developers at the Daily Scrum?\u00a0 (Choose three.)  ", "options": [{"content": "How is the Sprint proceeding?", "correct": false}, {"content": "What did I do yesterday that helped the Development Team meet the Sprint Goal?", "correct": true}, {"content": "Why were you late?", "correct": false}, {"content": "What will I do today to help the Development Team meet the Sprint Goal?", "correct": true}, {"content": "How many hours did I spend on the project yesterday?", "correct": false}, {"content": "What will I be working on tomorrow?", "correct": false}, {"content": "Do I see any impediment that prevents me or the Development Team from meeting the Sprint Goal?", "correct": true}], "feedback": "\u65e0"}, {"question": "What is the Developers responsible for? (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "Resolving internal team conflicts.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Reporting productivity.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Selecting the Product Owner.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Organizing the work required to meet the Sprint Goal.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "A Scrum Team is required to deliver a done Increment by the end of  a Sprint. Select two statements that explain what \u201cDone\u201d means.\u00a0 (Choose  two.)", "options": [{"content": "Ready for integration.", "correct": false}, {"content": "All work the Developers are willing to do.", "correct": false}, {"content": "No work left from the definition of \u201cDone\u201d.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Ready to be released to end users. ", "correct": true}, {"content": "Whatever the Product Owner defines as quality. ", "correct": false}], "feedback": "\u5b9e\u9645\u8003\u8bd5\u4e2d\u53ef\u80fd\u4f1a\u5c06\u9898\u76ee\u4e2d\u7684Scrum team \u6539\u6210Developers\uff0c\u4e0d\u5f71\u54cd\u7b54\u6848\uff0c2\u4e2a\u5173\u952e\u56e0\u7d20\uff0c1\uff09\u6ca1\u6709\u5269\u4e0b\u7684DoD\u30022\uff09Released to EU\u3002 "}, {"question": "Which\u00a0two\u00a0ways\u00a0of\u00a0creating\u00a0scrum\u00a0teams\u00a0are\u00a0consistent\u00a0with Scrum Value.", "options": [{"content": "The Chief Product Owner determines the new team structures and assignments.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Managers collaborate to assign individuals to specific teams.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Bring all the  people together and let them organize into Scrum Teams.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Managers personally re-assign current subordinates to new teams.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Existing teams propose how they would like to go about organizing into the new structure.", "correct": true}], "feedback": "\u6b64\u9898\u5728\u8003\u8bd5\u4e2d\u4f1a\u6362\u4e2a\u5f62\u5f0f\u51fa\u73b0\uff0c\u9700\u8981\u7406\u89e3\u3002 "}, {"question": "Which two of the following are true about the Scrum Master role?\u00a0 (Choose the best two answers.)", "options": [{"content": "At the Sprint Review, the Scrum Master identifies what has been \"done\" and what has not been \"done\".", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Master teaches the Development Team to keep the Scrum meetings to their time-box.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Scrum Master helps those outside the team interact with the Scrum Team.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Scrum Master assigns tasks to Development Team members when they need work.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Master is responsible for updating the Sprint Burndown.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which two of the following are appropriate topics for discussion during a Sprint Retrospective?\u00a0 (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "Identifying high priority process improvements for the next Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The order of items in the Product Backlog.", "correct": false}, {"content": "How the team collaborates.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Documenting acceptance criteria for items in the next Sprint.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "The Daily Scrum is an event that happens every day. What would be three key concerns if the frequency were to be lowered to every two or three days?\u00a0 (Choose three.)", "options": [{"content": "Opportunities to inspect and adapt the Sprint Backlog are lost.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Impediments are raised and resolved more slowly.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Product Owner cannot accurately report progress to the stakeholders.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Too much work is spent updating the Scrum board before the meeting.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Master loses the ability to update the Gantt chart properly.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Sprint plan may become inaccurate.", "correct": true}], "feedback": "The Sprint plan may become inaccurate."}, {"question": "A Scrum Master is keeping a list of open impediments, but it is growing and he/she has been able to resolve only a small portion of the impediments. Which three techniques would be most helpful in this situation? (Choose three.)", "options": [{"content": "Consulting with the Development Team.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Prioritizing the list and working on them in order.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Arranging a triage meeting with all project managers.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Alerting management to the impediments and their impact.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "What are the two primary ways a Scrum Master keeps a Development Team working at its highest level of productivity?\u00a0 (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "By ensuring the meetings start and end at the proper time.", "correct": false}, {"content": "By removing impediments that hinder the Development Team.", "correct": true}, {"content": "By facilitating Development Team decisions.", "correct": true}, {"content": "By keeping high value features high in the Product Backlog.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "A Development Team selects a set of Product Backlog items for a Sprint  Backlog with the intent to get the selected items \u201cDone\u201d by the end of  the Sprint.   Which three phrases best describe the purpose of a definition of \u201cDone\u201d?\u00a0 (Choose three.)", "options": [{"content": "It controls whether the developers have performed their tasks.", "correct": false}, {"content": "It provides a template for elements that need to be included in the technical documentation.", "correct": false}, {"content": "It creates transparency over the work inspected at the Sprint Review.", "correct": true}, {"content": "It trucks the percent completeness of a Product Backlog item.", "correct": false}, {"content": "It guides the Development Team is creating a forecast at the Sprint Planning.", "correct": true}, {"content": "It defines what it takes for an Increment to be ready for release.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "In order to achieve the benefits of Scrum, it is important to enact the value of commitment. What two actions demonstrate the commitment of Scrum Team members?\u00a0 (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "Always deliver the items in the Sprint forecast.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Help the other Scrum Team members.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Do your best.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Send out a daily status report.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Work late.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Select three incorrect, untrue, or misleading statements about Scrum?", "options": [{"content": "Scrum is a framework for developing and sustaining complex products.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Scrum is based on empirical process control theory.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Scrum is like traditional processes but with self-organization to replace Project Managers.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Scrum is a framework that eliminates complexity.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Each component of Scrum serves a specific purpose and is essential to your ability to use Scrum to develop complex products.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Scrum is a methodology where you can pick and choose which parts of Scrum you think will work for your environment.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "Which Scrum Values are exhibited by not building Product Backlog items that have low business value?\u00a0 (Choose three.)", "options": [{"content": "Economic Value Added.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Respect.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Focus.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Earned Value.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Courage.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "Which are properties of the Daily Scrum?\u00a0 (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "It is facilitated by the team lead.", "correct": false}, {"content": "It is held first thing in the morning.", "correct": false}, {"content": "It is fifteen minutes or less in duration.", "correct": true}, {"content": "It is free from and designed to promote conversation.", "correct": false}, {"content": "It consists of the Scrum Master asking the Team members the three questions.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Its location and time remain constant.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "What two factors are best considered when establishing the Sprint length?\u00a0 (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "The organization has mandated similar length sprints.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The level of uncertainty over the technology to be used.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The frequency at which team formation can be changed.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The risk of being disconnected from the stakeholders.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "In the Sprint Planning meeting, the Product Owner and the Development Team were unable to reach a clear understanding about the highest order Product Backlog items. Because of this, the Development Team couldn't figure out how many Product Backlog items it could forecast for the upcoming Sprint. They were able to agree on a Sprint Goal, however. Which of the following two actions should the Scrum Master support?\u00a0 (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "Cancel the Sprint. Send the entire team to an advanced Scrum training and then start a new Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Forecast the most likely Product Backlog items to meet the goal and create a Sprint Backlog based on a likely initial design and plan. Once the time-box for the Sprint Planning meeting is over, start the Sprint and continue to analyze, decompose, and create additional functionality during the Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Continue the Sprint Planning meeting past its time-box until an adequate number of Product Backlog items are well enough understood for the Development Team to make a complete forecast. Then start the Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Discuss in the upcoming Sprint Retrospective why this happened and what changes will make it less likely to recur.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Ask everyone to take as much time as needed to analyze the Product Backlog first, and then reconvene another Sprint Planning meeting.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which two activities will a Product Owner engage in during a Sprint?\u00a0 (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "Run the Daily Scrum.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Prioritize the Development Team's work on the Sprint Backlog.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Update the Sprint burndown chart.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Answer questions from the Development Team about items in the current Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Work with the stakeholders.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "Which three behaviors demonstrate that a Scrum Team is self-managing?\u00a0 (Choose the best three answers) ", "options": [{"content": "The Scrum Team members are working within the boundaries of their functional description and nicely handing off work from analyst to developer to tester to integration. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Scrum Team has all the skills needed to create an Increment. ", "correct": true}, {"content": "Stakeholders are attending the Daily Scrum to check progress and work with the Scrum Master to optimize the functional scope for the Sprint. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Developers collaboratively selecting their own work during the Sprint. ", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Scrum Master is no longer needed. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Developers create their own Sprint Backlog, reflecting all work that is part of Definition of Done. ", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "Which are characteristics of the Daily Scrum? (Choose the best two answer). ", "options": [{"content": "Its purpose is to inspect progress towrard the Sprint Goal and adapt the Sprint Backlog. ", "correct": true}, {"content": "It is facilitated by the team lead. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "It is free form and designed to promote conversation. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "It consists of the Scrum Master asking the team for status. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Its location and time remain constant. ", "correct": true}, {"content": "It is held first thing in the morning. ", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which of the following are true about the length of the Sprint?\u00a0 (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "The length of the Sprint should be proportional to the work that is done in between Sprints.", "correct": false}, {"content": "It is best to have Sprints of consistent length throughout a development effort.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Sprint length is determined during Sprint Planning, and should hold the time it will take to code the planned features in the upcoming Sprint, but does not include time for any testing.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Sprint length is determined during Sprint Planning, and should be long enough to make sure the Development Team can deliver what is to be accomplished in the upcoming Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "All Sprints must be 1 month or less.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "A Scrum Team is cohesive unit of professionals that consists of which of the following? (Choose all that apply) ", "options": [{"content": "One Product Owner ", "correct": true}, {"content": "One Scrum Master ", "correct": true}, {"content": "Users ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Customers. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Developers. ", "correct": true}], "feedback": "Scrum\u56e2\u961f\u7684\u6784\u6210\u3002 "}, {"question": "A Development Team selects a set of Product Backlog items for a Sprint Backlog with the intent to get the selected items `Done` by the end of the Sprint. Which three phrases best describe the purpose of a definition of `Done`?\u00a0 (Choose three.)", "options": [{"content": "It controls whether the developers have performed their tasks.", "correct": false}, {"content": "It provides a template for elements that need to be included in the technical documentation.", "correct": false}, {"content": "It creates transparency over the work inspected at the Sprint Review.", "correct": true}, {"content": "It trucks the percent completeness of a Product Backlog item.", "correct": false}, {"content": "It guides the Development Team is creating a forecast at the Sprint Planning.", "correct": true}, {"content": "It defines what it takes for an Increment to be ready for release.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "You are the Scrum Master for four Scrum Teams working from the same Product Backlog. Several of the developers come to you complaining that work identified for the upcoming two Sprints will require full-time commitment from a technical specialist who is external to the teams. What are two key concerns for the Scrum Master to take into account in this situation?\u00a0 (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "The desire to maintain a stable velocity.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The benefit of Development Teams figuring out a solution for themselves.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The need to have enough work to keep all Development Team members busy.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The ability of the Development Teams to produce integrated Increments.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "One of the Scrum events is the Daily Scrum. What are two intended outcomes of the Daily Scrum?\u00a0 (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "A shared understanding of the most important work to be undertaken next to achieve the best possible progress toward the Sprint goal.", "correct": true}, {"content": "An update of completed tasks and of the remaining work so the Scrum Master can plan the next day.", "correct": false}, {"content": "A status report for the upper management indicating what each individual has done, will be doing, and what is impending him/her.", "correct": false}, {"content": "An updated Scrum board to make Sprint progress transparent for the stakeholders.", "correct": false}, {"content": "New impediments for the Scrum Master to take care of.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "One of the Scrum events is the Daily Scrum. What are two intended outcomes of the Daily Scrum?\u00a0 (Choose two)", "options": [{"content": "A status report for the upper management indicating what each individual has done, will be doing, and what is impending him/her.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Identification of impediments that may prevent the Developers from achieving the Sprint Goal ", "correct": true}, {"content": "A shared understanding of the most important work to be undertaken next to achieve teh best possible progress toward the Sprint Goal. ", "correct": true}, {"content": "An update of completed tasks and of the remaining work so the Scrum Master can plan the next day.", "correct": false}, {"content": "An updated Scrum board to make Sprint progress transparent for the stakeholders.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "\u90fd\u548cSprint Goal\u76f8\u5173\u3002\u7b54\u6848B\u53ef\u80fd\u4f1a\u4ee5\u5176\u4ed6\u4e0d\u540c\u7684\u8868\u8fbe\u65b9\u5f0f\u51fa\u73b0\u5728\u8003\u8bd5\u4e2d\u3002\u9700\u8981\u6ce8\u610f\u3002 "}, {"question": "Which two things should the Development Team do during the first Sprint?\u00a0 (Choose two)", "options": [{"content": "Make up a plan for the rest of the project.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Analyze, describe, and document the requirements for the subsequent Sprints.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Develop at least one piece of functionality.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Analyze, design, and describe the complete architecture and infrastructure.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Create an increment of potentially releasable software.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "What are two good ways for a Scrum Team to ensure security concerns are satisfied?\u00a0 (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "Postpone the work until a specialist can perform a security audit and create a list of security-related Product Backlog items.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Add security concerns to the definition of \u201cDone\u201d.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Add a Sprint to specifically resolve all security concerns.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Delegate the work to the concerned department.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Have the Scrum Team create Product Backlog items for each concern.", "correct": true}], "feedback": "\u65e0"}, {"question": "What is the Developers responsible for?\u00a0 (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "Resolving internal team conflicts.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Reporting productivity.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Selecting the Product Owner.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Organizing the work required to meet the Sprint Goal.", "correct": true}], "feedback": "\u65e0"}, {"question": "A new member has just joined an existing Development Team that has been together for several Sprints. During the Sprint, the individual has been trying to share his ideas and viewpoints but is continuously ignored by the rest of the Development Team. Which three Scrum Values has the Development Team been neglecting? (Choose three.)", "options": [{"content": "Commitment", "correct": false}, {"content": "Respect", "correct": true}, {"content": "Transparency", "correct": false}, {"content": "Focus", "correct": false}, {"content": "Openness", "correct": true}, {"content": "Courage", "correct": true}], "feedback": "Scrum \u7684Value\uff0c\u770bScrum Guide\uff0c\u90fd\u6709\u63d0\u5230\u3002 "}, {"question": "Which two ways of creating Development Teams are consistent with Scrum's values? (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "Existing teams propose how they would like to go about organizing into the new structure.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Managers personally re-assign current subordinates to new teams.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Managers collaborate to assign individuals to specific teams.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Bring all the developers together and let them self-organize into Development Teams.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Chief Product Owner determines the new team structures and assignments.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "\u6ca1\u6709Managers\u548cChief product owner "}, {"question": "A Development Team is required to deliver a done Increment by the end of  a Sprint. Select two statements that explain what \u201cDone\u201d means.\u00a0 (Choose  two.)", "options": [{"content": "All work the Development Team is willing to do.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Ready for integration.", "correct": false}, {"content": "No work left from the definition of \u201cDone\u201d.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Whatever the Product Owner defines as quality.", "correct": false}, {"content": "All work to create software that is ready to be released to end users.", "correct": true}], "feedback": "\u5b9e\u9645\u8003\u8bd5\u4e2d\uff0c\u53ef\u80fd\u4f1a\u5c06\u9898\u76ee\u4e2d\u7684Development team\u6362\u6210Scrum Team\uff0c\u7b54\u6848\u4e0d\u53d8\u3002 "}, {"question": "Several Sprints into a project, the Product Owner tells the Scrum Master that a key stakeholder just started using the product. The stakeholder is unhappy with the quality of the product. What are two good options for the Scrum Master?\u00a0 (Choose the best two answers.)", "options": [{"content": "Wait to bring this up until the Sprint Retrospective.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Encourage the Product Owner to put quality specifications on the Product Backlog and express the stakeholder's concern to the Developers.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Bring the concern to the testers to improve how the Product is verified.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Explain to the Product Owner that it is up to the Developers to decide on acceptable quality standards.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Coach the Product Owner on how to talk with the Developers about this concern.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "What two techniques could the Scrum Master use when the Scrum Team gets caught in an internal disagreement about which development techniques to apply? (Choose the best two answers.)", "options": [{"content": "Involve the complete Development Team. ", "correct": true}, {"content": "Use coaching techniques; such as open questions and active listening. ", "correct": true}, {"content": "Ask an external technical specialist to make the decision. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Send every team member to the company's HR department to express their concerns.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "You\u00a0have\u00a0just\u00a0been hired by a company new to Scrum. Your management has assigned you to be the Scrum Master of six new Scrum Teams. These teams will build one product. Select two conditions you should strive for in this Scenario.  (Choose two)", "options": [{"content": "There should be only one Product Owner. ", "correct": true}, {"content": "There should be six Product Owners, reporting to a Chief Product Owner. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "There should be six Product Owners, one for each Scrum Team. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "Each Scrum Team should has a separate Product Backlog. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "The product has one Product Backlog. ", "correct": true}], "feedback": "\u9898\u76ee\u7684\u5173\u952e\u8bcd\u662fone product\uff0c\u6240\u4ee5\u53ea\u80fd\u6709\u4e00\u4e2aPO\u548c\u4e00\u4e2aPB\u3002 "}, {"question": "Which three of the following are feedback loops in Scrum?\u00a0 (Choose three.)", "options": [{"content": "Sprint Review.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Release Planning.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Sprint Retrospective.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Refinement Meeting.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Daily Scrum.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "What are two ways that regulatory\u00a0compliance issues are dealt with in Scrum? \u00a0(Choose the best two answers) ", "options": [{"content": "They are addressed by a separate team who is responsible for compliance issues. ", "correct": false}, {"content": "They are discussed, determined, and documented before the actual feature development Sprints. ", "correct": true}, {"content": "They are added to the Product backlog and addressed in early Sprints, while always requiring at least some business functionality, no matter how small. ", "correct": true}, {"content": "They are addressed along with functional development of the product. ", "correct": false}], "feedback": "\u5c5e\u4e8enon-function\u7684\u9700\u6c42\uff0c\u7c7b\u4f3c\u5b89\u5168\u529f\u80fd\uff0c\u6240\u4ee5PB\u4e2d\u5fc5\u987b\u52a0\u5165\uff0c\u5e76\u4e14\u6bcf\u4e2aSprints\u4e2d\u90fd\u8981\u8ba8\u8bba\u3002\u6b64\u9898\u4ee5\u524d\u8003\u7684\u662fnon-function\uff0c\u73b0\u5728\u53d8\u6210\u4e86 "}, {"question": "Currently, your Development Teams are organized to address a single  layer only (for example, front end, middle tier, back end, and  interfaces). What are three things to consider when deciding to move away from such component teams toward feature teams?\u00a0 (Choose three.)", "options": [{"content": "You cannot do Scrum without feature teams.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Productivity may suffer when making this kind of move", "correct": true}, {"content": "Getting support from the business side first helps.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Feature teams have less communication overhead.", "correct": true}, {"content": "With feature teams, it is easier to calculate the productivity per team.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "A Scrum Team has been working on a product for nine Sprints. A new Product Owner comes in, understanding he is accountable for the Product Backlog. However, he is unsure about his responsibilities.Which two activities are part of the Product Owner role according to Scrum?\u00a0 (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "Ensuring that the most valuable functionality is produced first, at all times.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Interacting with stakeholders.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Providing the Development Team with detailed specifications.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Describing features as Use Cases.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Creating detailed functional test cases.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "\u65e0"}, {"question": "During a Sprint Retrospective, the Developers proposes moving the Daily Scrum to only occur on Tuesdays and Thursdays. Which two are the most appropriate responses for the Scrum Master?\u00a0 (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "Consider the request and decide on which days the Daily Scrum should occur.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Coach the team on why the Daily Scrum is important as an opportunity to update the plan.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Have the developers vote.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Learn why the Development Team wants this and work with them to improve the outcome of the Daily Scrum.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Acknowledge and support the self-organizing team\u2019s decision.", "correct": false}], "feedback": "\u65e0"}, {"question": "What are two good ways for the Development Team to make non-functional requirements visible?\u00a0 (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "Put them on a separate list on the Scrum board, available for all to see.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Add them to the Product Backlog and keep the Product Owner posted on the expected effort.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Run the integration and regression tests before the end of the Sprint, and capture the open work for the Sprint Backlog of the next Sprint.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Add them to the definition of \u201cDone\u201d so the work is taken care of every Sprint.", "correct": true}], "feedback": "\u65e0"}, {"question": "Which\u00a0two\u00a0of\u00a0the\u00a0following\u00a0are\u00a0true\u00a0about\u00a0the\u00a0Scrum\u00a0Master? \u00a0(Choose\u00a0the\u00a0best\u00a0two\u00a0answers.)", "options": [{"content": "The\u00a0Scrum\u00a0Master\u00a0assigns\u00a0tasks\u00a0to\u00a0Developers\u00a0when\u00a0they\u00a0need\u00a0work.  ", "correct": false}, {"content": "The\u00a0Scrum\u00a0Master\u00a0is\u00a0responsible\u00a0for\u00a0updating\u00a0the\u00a0Sprint\u00a0Burndown.  ", "correct": false}, {"content": "The\u00a0Scrum\u00a0Master\u00a0helps\u00a0those\u00a0outside\u00a0the\u00a0team\u00a0interact\u00a0with\u00a0the\u00a0Scrum\u00a0Team.  ", "correct": true}, {"content": "At\u00a0the\u00a0Sprint\u00a0Review,\u00a0the\u00a0Scrum\u00a0Master\u00a0identifies\u00a0what\u00a0has\u00a0been\u00a0done\u00a0and\u00a0not\u00a0done", "correct": false}, {"content": "The\u00a0Scrum\u00a0Master\u00a0teaches\u00a0the\u00a0Scrum\u00a0Team\u00a0to\u00a0use\u00a0timeboxes.  ", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "Which of the following are true about the Product Owner role? (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "The Product Owner is one person.", "correct": true}, {"content": "The Product Owner is accountable for ordering the Product Backlog.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Multiple people can share the Product Owner role on a Scrum Team.", "correct": false}, {"content": "The Product Owner role can be played by a committee or a team of people.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Which two things should the Development Team do during the first Sprint?\u00a0 (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "Make up a plan for the rest of the project.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Analyze, describe, and document the requirements for the subsequent Sprints.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Develop at least one piece of functionality.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Analyze, design, and describe the complete architecture and infrastructure.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Create an increment of potentially releasable software.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "What is a Development Team responsible for?\u00a0 (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "Resolving internal team conflicts.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Reporting productivity.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Selecting the Product Owner.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Organizing the work required to meet the Sprint Goal.", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "The Product Owner is not collaborating with the Development Team during the Sprint. What are two valuable actions for a Scrum Master to take?\u00a0 (Choose two.)", "options": [{"content": "Inform the Product Owner's functional manager.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Stop the Sprint, send the Product Owner to a course and restart.", "correct": false}, {"content": "Bring up the problem in the Sprint Retrospective.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Coach the Product Owner in the values of Scrum and incremental delivery.", "correct": true}, {"content": "Nominate a proxy Product Owner.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Every Development Team should have: (Chose the best )", "options": [{"content": "At least one representative from each major software engineering discipline (like QA, Dev, UX).", "correct": false}, {"content": "The competencies and skills needed to deliver a Done Increment in a Sprint.", "correct": true}, {"content": "One Lead Developer and no more than 8 other members.", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "When multiple teams work together on the same product, each team should maintain a separate Product Backlog.", "options": [{"content": "\u6b63\u786e", "correct": false}, {"content": "\u9519\u8bef", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "The Sprint Backlog is a result of Sprint Planning, and it includes the Sprint Goal.", "options": [{"content": "\u6b63\u786e", "correct": true}, {"content": "\u9519\u8bef", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "Cross-functional teams are optimized to work on one component or layer of a system only.  ", "options": [{"content": "\u6b63\u786e", "correct": false}, {"content": "\u9519\u8bef", "correct": true}], "feedback": "\u6709\u65f6\u5019Component\u4f1a\u6362\u6210Technical"}, {"question": "An Increment must be released to customers or rusers at the end of each Sprint.", "options": [{"content": "\u6b63\u786e", "correct": false}, {"content": "\u9519\u8bef", "correct": true}], "feedback": "\u4e0d\u662f\u5fc5\u987b\u8981Released\u3002"}, {"question": "A high-performance Scrum Team ensures that each Increment is complete by running a Release Sprint.", "options": [{"content": "\u6b63\u786e", "correct": false}, {"content": "\u9519\u8bef", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "To get started in terms of what to build, Scrum requires no more than a Product Owner with enough ideas for a first Sprint, a Development Team to implement those ideas and a Scrum Master to help guide the process.", "options": [{"content": "\u6b63\u786e", "correct": true}, {"content": "\u9519\u8bef", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "A Scrum Master is essentially the same thing as a traditional PM (Project Manager).", "options": [{"content": "\u6b63\u786e", "correct": false}, {"content": "\u9519\u8bef", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "The Scrum Team must choose at least one high priority process  improvement item, identified during the Sprint Retrospective, and place  it in the Sprint Backlog.", "options": [{"content": "\u6b63\u786e", "correct": false}, {"content": "\u9519\u8bef", "correct": true}], "feedback": "An earlier version of the Scrum Guide prescribed the practice of placing one improvement in the Sprint Backlog. This was removed in the 2020 update to the Scrum Guide because it was felt to be too prescriptive. However, if this practice provides value to you then you should adopt it. It is simply not prescribed anymore, but can still be valuable."}, {"question": "Multiple Scrum Teams working on the same product or system all select work from the same Product Backlog.", "options": [{"content": "\u6b63\u786e", "correct": true}, {"content": "\u9519\u8bef", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "The Product Owner makes sure the team selects enough from the Product Backlog for a Sprint to satisfy the stakeholders.", "options": [{"content": "\u6b63\u786e", "correct": false}, {"content": "\u9519\u8bef", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "Multiple Scrum Teams working on the same project must have the same Sprint start date.", "options": [{"content": "\u6b63\u786e", "correct": false}, {"content": "\u9519\u8bef", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "Cross-functional teams are optimized to work on one technical layer of a system only (e.g. GUI, database, middle tier, interfaces).", "options": [{"content": "\u6b63\u786e", "correct": false}, {"content": "\u9519\u8bef", "correct": true}], "feedback": "\u4e0d\u6b62One Technical Layer "}, {"question": "The purpose of a Sprint is to produce a done Increment of product.", "options": [{"content": "\u6b63\u786e", "correct": true}, {"content": "\u9519\u8bef", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "The Sprint Goal is a result of Sprint Planning, as is the Sprint Backlog.", "options": [{"content": "\u6b63\u786e", "correct": true}, {"content": "\u9519\u8bef", "correct": false}]}, {"question": "A properly functioning Scrum Team will have at least one Release Sprint and may well have several.", "options": [{"content": "\u6b63\u786e", "correct": false}, {"content": "\u9519\u8bef", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "Scrum is a methodology that tells in detail how to build software incrementally.", "options": [{"content": "\u6b63\u786e", "correct": false}, {"content": "\u9519\u8bef", "correct": true}]}, {"question": "Scrum has a role called \u201cProject Manager\u201d.", "options": [{"content": "\u6b63\u786e", "correct": false}, {"content": "\u9519\u8bef", "correct": true}], "feedback": "\u6ca1\u6709Project manager\u3002 "}]